All right, so right now we're
going to talk about an
application from 20,000 feet.
So this is going to be a very
high level overview of all of
the pieces of an application
that uses MongoDB, and how
they interact, and briefly talk
about the Mongo Shell,
and how it fits into
all of this.
All right, so the very
beginning, you have some
application.
So, this is your app, and it
provides some service.
Over here you have some clients,
and these clients are
making a request to
your application.
They may be web browsers, they
may be various other
applications.
They don't necessarily have
to be web browsers.
They could be anything that
needs some service from your
application.
They could be consuming
a REST API.
Basically, you'll have
clients, and
you'll have your server.
So that's kind of the model
we're dealing with right here.
So, this server will be running
Node.js in this class,
and basically at a high level,
what Node.js is, it's
basically a C++ program that
you control using V8
JavaScript.
So any applications you write
using Node.js will be written
in JavaScript, and it'll just
control this C++ application,
and you'll be able to say
something like, they made a
request for this resource, and
your application actually in
JavaScript will say, OK, if they
made a request for this
resource, I know how to respond
to that, and I'll
respond accordingly.
So, that's basically the
application part.
But if your application needs to
store persistent data now,
that's where MongoDB
would come in.
So here, the way this will work
is that your application
will actually make a
request to MongoDB.
It'll either be trying to store
data, it'll be trying to
retrieve data, update data, and
it'll make a request to
MongoDB to perform this
operation, and MongoDB will
reply with the return status, or
if you actually specify the
write concern, which we'll
talk about later, it'll
respond when the appropriate
persistence is reached.
Where you can say write concern
of my entire replica
set, and it will only respond
when your entire replica set
has been written to.
Also, the core server of
MongoDb, if you're curious, is
written in C++ as well.
So, that's how the components
work together.
We basically have this
application server interacting
directly with clients, and when
the application server
needs to store data
persistently, it actually acts
as the client communicating
with MongoDB, which is
listening for incoming requests,
and will actually
respond when the request
has been completed.
So, the other part of this is
that we actually have an
administrative shell.
So this is the Mongo Shell,
and it's a useful tool for
performing various
administrative tasks.
If you just want to take a quick
look at what's in your
database, this is a
very useful tool.
So, what is the Mongo
Shell exactly?
So, the Mongo Shell actually has
a lot of similarities with
Node.js itself, in that it's
also just a C++ program that
you control using V8.
So actually, when you open up
the mother shall you get a
prompt, and you can type various
commands into this
prompt, and the Mongo Shell
will then interpret these
commands using its own V8
bindings, and make requests to
MongoDB, and MongoDB
will respond.
And you can see the immediate
response in the shell.
So, this is useful for doing
things like asking various
questions about your
configuration, or even seeing
a bit of what you actually have
stored in your database,
or debugging of your
application.
So there's a sort of, you can
just think of this whole part
as the administrative
interface.
And this part is the
actual production
interface for your clients.
So, one last part of this
that'll be important just for
understanding this once you
actually start writing
applications, Node.js
applications, which is what
we'll be focusing on for this
course, is the way that
Node.js actually communicates
to MongoDB
is through the driver.
So, there's actually a library
that is available that you can
install, and use in your Node.js
application that
actually handles all the
connections to MongoDB, all of
the failover, all of
the wire protocol.
And basically in your
application, all you have to
do is use this API provided by
the driver, and it'll handle
the communication to
MongoDB for you.
So you can use this API to
insert documents, find
documents, or move documents,
and that'll all be handled by
the driver.