So let's talk about JSON.
So this is going to be an
introduction to JSON and the
JSON structure.
So we'll first talk
about the basic
structure of a JSON object.
Then we'll talk about
value types.
some basic nesting.
Then we'll talk about
some deep nesting.
So we'll go over each of those
individually and then come
back after each step.
All right.
So let's go into our Mongo shell
and let's use jsonintro.
All right, so first let's
do db.basic.find.
So this is a basic JSON object
that I inserted earlier.
Basically it has an _id field
and a name field.
So from this, you can get a
pretty good sense of what the
JSON format looks like.
It's meant to be a human
readable data format.
But if you type something
in JSON, any JSON
parser can accept it.
It's also generated by a lot
of different projects.
So the idea is that this whole
thing is a JSON object.
And the way you start a JSON
object is you actually have
the open curly brace, and inside
the curly brace you
actually have a bunch
of key value pairs.
So you have a key, then a colon,
and then the value.
And then if you want to have
another key value pair, you
put a comma here, and then a
key, colon, and another value.
And then if your object
is done, you use a
closed curly brace.
So that's the basic structure
of a JSON object.
This is a document
that I inserted
with "name", "MongoDB".
And MongoDB actually
automatically generated this
_id field which is meant
to be unique
across the whole system.
All right.
So this is the basic structure
of a JSON object.
All right.
So now we talk about a
basic JSON structure.
So next, let's actually
talk about the
values in our JSON structure.
You know, we've mentioned the
key value pairs, lets talk
about what the values
can actually be.
All right.
We're back in our Mongo shell
in the JSON intro database,
and let's just do
db.values.find.
And let's actually do
db.values.find().pretty() to
make this a little bit
easier to see.
All right.
So these are two values that
we have in our JSON intro
database and our values
collection.
So you see we have two
documents here.
And we actually have
a lot of different
types for our values.
So if you remember before, we
have these key value pairs, we
have the field name, and then
the actual value, then a
comma, field name colon value
then close braced
and our object.
So this is one JSON object,
two JSON objects.
So our collection actually has
two documents in it right now.
And you can tell because these
curly braces actually delimit
the beginning and end
of each JSON object.
So what I really wanted to point
out here is that the
values actually can have
different types.
So notice here we have
"name":"MongoDB.
MongoDB is in quotes, which
means it's a string type in
our JSON object.
Down here, we have
"database":"true, so we
actually have a Boolean
type right here.
Down here, we have "food":"pie
in quotes, means that's a
string type.
Down here we have
"price":"10.99".
You can see here that this is
actually a numeric type.
So the idea here is that we
actually can have different
types in our values.
Not only can we have different
types, we can actually have
completely different fields.
And we could have the
same field with
two different types.
So down here we could have
"database":"yes", if we
wanted, or "database":"no".
All right.
So the idea here is that you can
actually represent values
with completely different types
in a single JSON object.
So we talked about value types
in JSON and some of the
different ways you can represent
that, but actually
directly related to that
is the idea of nesting.
So not only can we have
different types for our
values, we can actually go
beyond just the primitive
types and actually have more
complicated structures.
So let's look at an
example of that.
All right.
So now we're back in
our Mongo shell.
We're going to look at some
examples of nested JSON
structures, so let's just
do the query here,
db.nested.find, then do
".pretty" to make
it easier to read.
So here we have two examples
of nested JSON structures.
So notice, like before, we have
our key value pairs, "id"
: "Objectid", "product"
: "car".
We have our string type,
car is in quotes.
But colors, actually,
is an array here.
So if you open with a square
bracket in JSON, that
indicates that you're starting
an array, and that actually
has a slightly different
syntax.
So in our array, we can have
just value comma value.
So we don't have keys
in our array.
It's kind of implicit, so you
can think of the key for red
as being zero, the key for this
value, black, as one.
So down here we have another
example of a nested structure.
We have our product key.
And we have the value of laptop,
that's a string.
Then we have our attributes,
which is
actually a nested object.
So since we're opening with a
curly brace, we actually are
indicating that the value of
attributes is an object
itself, which itself has
key value pairs.
So down here we have "type"
: "mac", "shiny" : "true",
"expensive" : "true".
And that's all in the attributes
sub-document or
sub-object.
All right.
So that's an example of using
nested structures in JSON.
All right.
So we talked a little bit about
basic nesting and JSON,
so now let's talk about some
more complicated structures
and really get into what we can
do with these nested JSON
structures.
So back in our shell, I'm going
to do a query on the
deep nested collection and
pretty print it so it makes it
easier to read.
So this document is a little
bit more complicated, so I
just have one in here.
This is an example of a more
complex nested structure and
kind of should give you an idea
of the variety of things
that we can represent using
these nested structures.
So just like before, we have
our key value pairs,
"class":"algegra" and
"students" colon.
And again, just like before,
we had an array.
But notice, inside our array
we don't have just string
values or Booleans, we actually
have an object.
So this shows that the values
of our array are just like
values in an object, they can
actually have any type,
including objects or arrays.
So this could be an array of
arrays, this could be an array
of objects, this could be an
array of objects, strings, and
Booleans all mixed together.
This is just showing our
nested structure.
So here we have our array.
In it is this object.
And we have keys and values in
this object "name" : "Susan",
"activities" colon, and
then this array.
And in this array we
also have objects.
We have objects for the
activities and they give more
description of what
the activities
are than simple strings.
So we could actually have
activities just be an array of
strings, but this is just to
show that we can represent
even more than that.
So we have an array, and inside
that we have an object.
Inside that we have an object
where one of the values is an
array which itself
contains objects.
So this is an example of
representing a deeply nested
structure in JSON.
So I'm going to talk a little
bit about how to use these
JSON objects in the shell, in
case you want to experiment
with this on your own.
So just to get started, let's
get this document out of our
deep nested collection
and assign it
to the course variable.
Let's print this out, see
what it looks like.
All right.
So we see our same nested
structure that we just found
in our deep nested collection.
So what we can do here is we can
actually access this just
like a normal JavaScript
object.
So we can actually do
course.students, and we see
our array of students.
Can also use bracket notation,
we get the same result.
So we can access this just
like we would a normal
JavaScript object and actually
what we can do is go deep into
the structure of
this document.
So we can actually do course
students and get the first
student in the "students" array,
and then do ".name".
So we've actually gone deep
in this document, and I'll
actually print that out again.
So we've actually gone deep into
this document and said,
we're getting this course
document looking at the
students array, looking at the
first element of the array
with this zero index, and then
just doing ".name" to get the
name out of the document
in the first
element of the array.
So not only can we read these
elements and see them as JSON,
we can actually modify them.
So let's say Susan wanted to be
called Sue, we could just
change the name and now if we
print out of our "students"
object, we can see down here
Susan has been replaced by Sue
in the name field of this
first student document.
So as a final note, if you want
to get more information
about JSON, what JSON really
is, and what qualifies as
valid JSON, you can actually
go to JSON.org and actually
see the complete JSON
specification.
All right.
So now it's time for our quiz.
Which of the following are
valid JSON documents?
So check all of these that
are valid JSON documents.