All right, so right now we're
going to talk about
asynchronous model versus
the synchronous model.
So, these are both names for
ways of handling operations
that don't require active work
on the part of the currently
running thread, or process.
So, usually when people talk
about these, they're
talking about IO.
So usually you hear asynchronous
IO versus
synchronous IO.
So now let's look at a real code
example of how this would
work in the Mongo Shell,
and in Node.js.
So, what I didn't mention before
is that the Mongo Shell
is actually synchronous, while
Node.js is actually
asynchronous.
So first, let's take a look at
a script for the Mongo Shell.
So, this is the synchronous
model that you probably are
more familiar with.
So, notice that what
we do here is
we're calling a fine0ne.
So you don't have to worry
about this right now, but
basically what fine0ne does is
just returns one document in
the collection call.
So, notice that we say var doc
equals db.coll.find0ne, just
like any other function call,
and the result is returned by
the call to fine0ne.
And after this function call
returns, we're free to print
the result.
So now let's take a
look at the same
script, but in Node.js.
So, we have some overhead
code to connect.
This is actually handled
automatically in the shell,
based on functions we pass
on the command line.
But here it's actually handled
as part of the application, so
you don't have to worry about
this part right now.
The main body of the
code is right here
after the call to fine0ne.
So, notice that what we do here
is we're also doing a
fine0ne, just like we were in
our synchronous Mongo Shell,
on the collection call, but
one difference you might
notice is that we're actually
not even bothering to check
the return value of
this call here.
What we're doing instead is
we're actually passing this
callback function.
And a common convention in
Node.js is for the callback
function to take an error as
the first parameter, and
return values as later
parameters.
In this case, we're kind of
ignoring the error and just
assuming it worked out, and
we're just printing the doc.
Printing our result.
And then this is
just more code.
You have to worry about
it right now.
Just closing the database.
So, what would actually happen
here is that we would call
db.collection.find0ne, and
this function would
immediately return, and we would
then get here, and print
out call to fine0ne.
And then after we actually make
the complete round trip
to our database and get a
response from MongoDB, we'll
print the result and close
our database connection.
So this callback gets called
only after our operation is
completely finished.
Now, this does look more
complicated than our script in
the Mongo Shell, and part of
that is just because we have
to have this extra code here
to connect to MongoDB, and
this extra code to close the
database, which is handled
automatically.
But part of it is that this
asynchronous model may be a
little strange at first, but the
advantage of this is that
this code can actually handle
many concurrent operations.
For example, if instead we put
this in a handler for our web
server and tried to get a
document each time a user
connected, we would be able to
handle a large number of users
without changing this code.
In contrast, the shell
would actually block.
What it calls fine0ne, it would
actually wait for the
result to come back, and all
other users would to wait.
So this case, we can just say
register our operation, keep
going, register more operations
for other users,
and handle all of those, and do
all of their IO operations
in parallel, whereas in the
Mongo Shell, we actually have
to do them completely
sequentially.
So, let's just do a quick
example of running this.
So to run the script,
all you have to do
is say mongo script.js.
This will connect to the test
database by default, and I put
in this document earlier.
The name, MongoDB.
Now, to run the node
application, all you have to
do is say node app.js, and that
will connect to MongoDB
in the test database as we
put in our application.
And we see we get the same
document back, but after we
see call to fine0ne.
All right, so that's the
difference between
asynchronous model and the
synchronous model, and I think
the Mongo Shell environment and
the Node.js environment,
and the differences between them
are a good example of the
differences between the
synchronous model and the
asynchronous model.