All right, so this is an
introduction to NPM.
NPM is the package manager
for node.js.
So we're going to talk a little
bit about packages, how
to use them, and how
to install them.
If you look in this directory,
we have two files-- we have
our app and we have this file
called package.json.
So let's just get started and
let's just run our app.
All right.
So we have a problem--
cannot find module express.
So let's look at our app
and try to figure out
what's going on.
So we have these require
statements.
These require statements are
actually how we include
external libraries in a
node.js application.
So here we're actually requiring
express, requiring
consolidate, and requiring
MongoDB.
So we actually depend on
all of these libraries.
So even though our application
doesn't do anything, we're
depending on all these libraries
for this example.
So the first thing we can do to
solve this problem is use
NPM install express.
So we saw that the error message
was "cannot find
module express", so let's
just install that
and see if it works.
All right, so we just
installed express.
Now, let's try to run
our application.
So we have another issue--
"cannot find module
consolidate." So if we go back
to our app, see, we don't just
include express, we require
consolidate and MongoDB.
So we could actually install
each of those individually, or
we could use our package.json
file.
So a lot of node.js applications
come with
package.json file, which
basically has some metadata
about the package, including
its dependencies.
So if we look in here, we can
see the name-- intro_to_npm--
we can see the version, and we
can see the description of the
package, and the entry point of
our application, and a list
of dependencies with
their versions.
So let's see what we can
do with this file.
So NPM actually knows about
this package.json file.
Se of we just type npm install,
NPM will actually
install automatically.
The packages in the
package.json file.
So now, if we try to run our
application, it runs
successfully.
One more thing that I want to
note about NPM is that it
installs local modules in the
node modules directory.
So you'll have to install the
dependencies locally for all
of our examples and stencil code
that we provide, even if
we don't show that step
in every video.
You could actually install them
globally, but for now,
we'll just cover installing
them in the node modules
directory for each application
that you write.
So we could take a look, just
to verify, that we've
installed the modules
that we expect.
We can see consolidate,
express and MongoDB.
So that's a basic introduction
to the
node.js package manager.
And that should be all you need
to complete this course.