All right, so we have our
simple Hello, World
application in express.
But there's one problem
with this.
So the issue is that here, in
our response, we're just
surveying this static
string every time.
What we really want to do send
back an HTML page, but at the
same time, we actually want to
change the contents of that
page programmatically.
So the way we can do this is
using a template library.
So the first thing we want to do
is make a directory for our
HTML pages.
So we're going to call this
directory Views and then let's
open views/hello.html.
And for this, let's just
do h1hello name.
We'll see what this means in a
bit, but basically, these two
curly braces on either side of
"name" is special syntax for
the template engine that we're
going to use in this example.
All right, so now let's go
back to our application.
And let's actually include
our template engine.
So we're actually going to use
a library called Consolidate.
And what Consolidate is
basically a set of wrappers
for a number of template
libraries for "express." So
it's just that "express"
requires template libraries to
have a certain interface,
and "consolidate"
handles that for us.
So what this allows us to do
is go down here and say
app.engine--
set the module HTML
to be cons.swig.
So swig is actually the
template engine
we're going to be using.
And we're using "consolidate"
so that we can integrate it
directly with "express."
So now that we've registered
that module, we can say
app.set and set our
view engine for
"express" to be HTML.
And the last thing we need to
do is tell it where to look
for the views.
So we say app.set views to be
__dirname, current directory
plus the views directory.
All right, so now we've
registered swig, our template
engine with "express".
And then we've told it where
to look for our HTML files.
So now let's actually
generate a template.
So instead of sending the static
string and result.send,
we'll actually do
result.render.
And we look for the
page "hello".
It will automatically add
the HTML extension.
And we actually give it a
dictionary with one key name,
and the value of swig.
So this is going to be
passed directly to
our template engine.
So let's see how
this all works.
So let's run our application.
And we're missing the
module again.
So let's just do npm install
consolidate.
We've got a few warnings, but
it looks like "consolidate"
installed successfully.
Now let's do npm install swig,
since we know we're using that
as our template engine.
All right, so now let's
do node.app--
touch js again.
Now our server's listening
on port 8080.
So let's go back
to our browser.
Local host 8080 and we
get Hello, Swig!.
So if you go back to
our application--
cancel this, your out-dot js.
What's actually happening here
is that we get a request
that's handled by this
Handler here.
And then we call response.render
with "hellow"
and this hash--
so name as the key,
swig as the value.
And what that does it is
actually loads hello.html.
And name here is actually going
to be whatever name we
pass in the hash.
So that's how to use "swig" with
"express" to create HTML
templates on the server side.
This is just meant to be
a very simple example.
And there's actually a lot out
there in terms of client side
rendering, but we're not going
to cover that in this course.