All right, the answer is the
missing node will be
discovered, as long as you list
at least one valid node.
So the driver will actually
automatically detect that the
node you listed is a Replica Set
member and then detect all
the other ones, and
connect to those.
But remember that if you have
a Replica Set, and that node
happens to be down, you may
have an actual primary and
actual secondary, you may have
the majority of the nodes up,
but you won't be able to connect
just because you
haven't given any nodes that
happen to be up at the time.
So it's probably best to add all
the members, but it will
automatically discover them, if
you happen to accidentally
leave some out.