All right.
So now let's talk about replica
set failover in the
node.js driver.
So just to recap, when you're
sending writes or operations
from the driver, writes will
go to the primary.
So all writes will go to the
primary node in a replica set.
The reads, by default, will
go to the primary.
Although, you can configure them
to go elsewhere, which
we'll actually cover
in later sections.
So the question now is, what
happens when a node in the
replica set goes down?
Because that's actually
the whole purpose
of the replica set.
You have copies of your data,
because you want high
availability and sort
of more durability.
So the question we have now is,
what actually happens in
that situation where this node
just gets blasted off the face
of the earth?
How do we need to respond?
And how does the
driver respond?
So it turns out, in the node.js
driver, what actually
happens is that the writes
that come in from our
application and the reads that
can't yet be sent to a primary
but that need to be sent
to a primary are
buffered in the driver.
So from the application
perspective, you see that
you're dispatching all these
reads and writes, you just
don't see them complete yet.
So the driver will actually
buffer these until the
failover completes and you
have a new primary.
Then it will send all
the operations.
Then the client application will
get all the responses,
and you'll see all the writes
and reads complete as they
normally would.
So let's look at an example
of how this looks
in application code.
So this is the example we're
going to be using to
demonstrate this failover
behavior that I was just
talking about.
And you'll notice that most
of this is the same.
We still are doing normal
Insert call.
We still have this connection
string here.
What we're doing a little bit
differently is using this
setTimeout function.
So what the setTimeout function
does is it actually
registers the callback you give
it and calls it after
this timeout expires.
So this is saying, call the
function, insertDocument,
which is the function we're
already in, after 1 second or
1,000 milliseconds.
So what this code will
actually do is
it'll come down here--
this is just a declaration, so
nothing's being executed yet.
But then we get down here and we
call insertDocument, which
calls this function, which will
dispatch an Insert and
just continue on down here,
because we're actually doing
this asynchronously.
We don't have to wait until
we get a response.
So we immediately come down
here and say, Dispatched
insert, and then register this
function to be called again in
1,000 milliseconds.
So the result will be one Insert
every second, because
this function will get called
once, register itself to be
called again in one second.
It will get called again,
register itself to get called
again in one second, get
called again, and
so on and so on.
So this is effectively like a
For loop with a sleep of one
second where we're just calling
Insert repeatedly.
One difference is that we
don't have to wait for a
response from Insert
before we sleep.
So we don't have to do any
complicated logic like, say,
how long do we need to sleep?
Because we actually took half a
second to do the Insert and
get the response, let's sleep
only for half a second.
This one's a little simpler in
that respect, because we could
just sleep for a second.
And because we're not waiting
for a response, there aren't
as many variables that we have
to think about, because we
don't have to factor in the time
it took to get a response
from this Insert.
We could just sleep for a second
and get pretty close to
one Insert per second.
So that's one difference is this
asynchronous call here.
The other difference is this
is not actually the same
execution context.
This is actually just
registering a callback.
It's not like we have a single
thread going to sleep.
So one side effect is that if we
call insertDocument, we can
actually call it twice.
What that'll do is call this
function twice, it'll register
itself again twice.
So in the next second, it'll
get called twice again and
called twice again and called
twice again and so on.
Another thing you can do that's
even crazier is you
could put setTimeout, this
line here, twice.
Now, what that'll do is just
exponentially increase the
number of times this
function is called.
So it'll get called the first
time, it'll register itself
twice, then it'll get called
twice, and register itself
twice per call.
So it'll register itself four
times in the next second, then
eight times in the next second,
then 16 times, then 32
times, and rapidly grow in
powers of two until you're
inserting hundreds of thousands
of documents a second.
So that's kind of
an interesting
side effect of this.
I'd recommend taking some time
to play with this function,
copy this line or this line over
a few times, and just see
what happens.
It's an interesting result.
So this is basically the example
we're going to use to
demonstrate failover.
All you really need to know is
that it's basically a For loop
that's dispatching Insert
operations.
And we should see the responses
as they come in,
because this is an asynchronous
program and we're
inserting documents that have
increasing document numbers.
So let's run this application
and see what happens.
All right.
So we're running our
application.
And as expected, we see a
dispatched Insert before we
get a response.
So this is the log message
saying that we
sent our Insert out.
And this is the log that we have
in our Insert callback
that we actually received
the document.
So let's take a look
at what happens
when we do the failover.
So first, let's connect
to local host 30,001.
And conveniently, we see that
it says it's the PRIMARY in
the prompt.
So we don't really
have to check.
We just know that this
is the PRIMARY.
So let's actually
just completely
shut this server down.
It's called db.shutdownServer.
So we actually have
to be an admin.
I don't have authentication,
so I can just use the admin
database and then shut
down the server.
So now we've shut down our
server, we look over here and
we see some interesting
side effects.
We don't see any errors that
would result from our callback
being called.
We just see this dispatched
Insert message.
So let's go back up there
and take a closer look.
So the interesting thing
to note here is that we
dispatched all of these Inserts
and we're still
dispatching an Insert
per second, but we
don't get any responses.
We also don't get any errors.
There's nothing calling
back to our callbacks.
We're just dispatching these
operations, and they seem to
just be taking longer
than usual.
But then we look down here.
Once the failover completes,
we see this huge batch of
operations suddenly
come through.
So at this point, the failover
was done, the driver sent out
all the operations that had
buffered when we were sending
out one per second.
And we kind of get
these operations
back in one big block.
So that's what happens in the
failover case is that the
driver actually just buffers the
operations you're sending.
So they just seem to take a
little longer than usual.
And then when the election is
done, the driver will send all
the operations and you'll
receive callbacks for the
results as you normally would
just as if the operation took
longer than usual.
So that's pretty much all you
need to know about dealing
with failover in node.js is that
the driver does a lot of
it for you.
So you really don't have to
worry too much about writing
code in your application to
deal with this situation.
All right.
So let's take a quiz on
failover in node.js.
All right, so the question is,
what will happen if this
Insert occurs during
a primary election?
So if you make this call while
an election is happening, what
will happen?
Is it, the Insert will
immediately succeed and the
callback will be called?
Is it, the Insert will
fail with an error?
Is it, the Insert will be
buffered until the election
completes, then the callback
will be after the operation is
sent and a response
is received?
Or is it, the callback will be
called first, then the Insert
will be buffered until the
election completes?