All right, so this is the
solution for Homework 3.3, and
our goal was to add a
comment to a post.
So if you remember,
the post actually
has an array of comments.
So the way we add a comment to
the post is we actually have
to push it on the end
of the array.
So for this we use an update.
And this is actually an in-place
update because we're
actually using this
$push operator.
So what we do is we do a query
based on the permalink of the
post we're trying to comment
on and then use $push to
actually push on the end
of this comments array.
And then we pass in a callback,
takes an error, and
the number of documents
or modified.
So if we have an error, we
actually call back with the
error and no result.
If we've succeeded in doing our
update, we just call the
original callback.
So this is the solution
to Homework 3.3.