All right.
So now we're going to talk about
the Node.js driver and
CRUD operations using MongoDB.
So you've already been using
the Mongo shell to do these
CRUD operations doing create,
remove, update, delete, having
them converted to BSON by the
shell, and sent to MongoDB.
So now what we're going to do
is we're going to talk about
the Node.js driver.
And we're actually going to
write some application code
that uses the Node.js MongoDB
driver, and takes your
queries, converts them to BSON,
uses a wire protocol,
communicates with MongoDB.
So this section is just going
to be about how to use the
Node.js driver, and what the
interface is to the driver.
So the first thing we need to
do is actually get some data
into the database.
So let's go do that.
So I actually have this
file, grades.json.
And basically, it has one JSON
object per line, has a
student, assignment, grade.
And we want to import
this into MongoDB.
So the way we can do that is we
actually say, mongoimport,
and then we give it
a database name.
We'll use the course database.
And we'll use the grades
collection.
And import grades.json.
All right.
So we just imported the grades
into the database.
Imported 16 objects.
So let's just check that.
So we can connect using the
Mongo shell, use course.
To get to the course database,
we can do db.grades.find.
We can see we actually imported
all these grades
documents, so we can use
these when we're
writing our example programs.
So this program is an example
of using findOne with the
Node.js driver.
So the first thing we have to do
is require MongoDB to make
sure we actually have a
reference to the driver.
So we say for our MongoClient,
require('mongodb').MongoClient.
The next thing we
do is actually
connect to the database.
A simple way to do this
is just to say
MongoClient.connect, and then
give it a connection string.
And you can actually look
through the docs for the
format of the string for things
like a replica set or a
sharded cluster.
But for now, we're just
connecting to a single MongoD.
So this MongoD is running on the
host, local host, and the
port, 27107.
And we're saying that
we want to connect
to the course database.
So we give it a callback.
So we say once you're connected,
call this, with the
error and a connected
database.
So down here, if there's an
error, we just throw.
And what we're doing here we
are saying, I want to query
for all the students that got
100 on any assignment.
So we say
db.collection('grades').
Take our already connected
database and just say, this is
the collection we care about.
And then we do findOne
with our query.
And we get findOne callback with
an error and a document.
So what this does is it will
perform the findOne query
against MongoDB.
Call the callback with the
document that we found.
And then we just log
into the console.
So let's just run this
application, and we see we've
logged one document
to the console.
Student 'Joe', assignment
'exam', grade 100.
Underscore ID was automatically
generated when
we ran Mongo import.
Now, you may notice that the
value of the underscore ID
field just looks like this giant
hex string, but it's
really an object ID type.
If you remember in the shell, it
looked a little different.
But all that really means is
that the two string method of
an object ID, which is the
function we call when we want
to get the string representation
of the object
ID, is different in the Node.js
driver from the way it
is in the Mongo shell.
So that's why you see the
different representation here
when we try to print out a JSON
object that includes an
object ID .
So
That's an example of using
findOne with MongoDB.
What if we want to find more
than one document?
This is an example of using
find with MongoDB.
And it's pretty close,
but there are a
few things to note.
So we connect in exactly
the same way.
We're using exactly
the same query.
But here what we're doing is
we're saying, db.collection('g
rades').find(query).
And we actually don't give
this a callback.
And we'll actually talk a little
bit about that later.
But basically, what
this is doing is
making a cursor object.
And on the cursor object, we can
say, .toArray, which tells
the cursor we want all our
documents that result from
this query to be returned
as an array.
So this takes a callback,
has error, documents.
If there's an error,
we want to throw.
Otherwise, we just say, log the
documents to the console.
So now we can run this.
We see we get back on array
of all the documents where
students got 100 on
their assignment.
So there's something else I want
to mention about find,
and for that we have an example
that sort of separates
the pieces and makes it more
obvious what's going on.
So here we connect in exactly
the same way.
We're using exactly
the same query.
But we're doing something
a little different here.
We're actually assigning cursor
to db.collection.('
grades').find(query).
And the interesting thing about
this is it means that
this call is synchronous.
It's actually just returning our
cursor rather than taking
a callback.
So this is actually an important
insight into what's
actually happening underneath.
So this is actually just
creating a cursor object.
It's not actually
doing the query.
So the point of the cursor is
just to describe our query,
and describe what we're
looking for.
We actually don't perform the
query until we need some
documents back.
So in our last example,
it was toArray.
We did db.collection.('
grades').find.(toArray).
And when we did that toArray
call, the Node.js
driver said, OK.
The user actually is looking
for all the documents, and
wants it back in an array.
And so we actually have
to go do the query.
In this case, we actually
haven't asked for anything
yet, so it can just make the
cursor object and not have to
do any extra work.
But now, on this cursor
object, we can
call the .each method.
This method actually
takes a callback.
And this callback is called
for each document that's
returned from the database.
So if there's an error,
we throw error.
If doc equals null, that
actually means our cursor has
been exhausted.
We're at the end
of our cursor.
This function won't get called
again, so we can actually
safely close the database.
And if doc isn't null, we log
it and we say, this student
got a good grade.
So this is an example of how
cursors work in MongoDB.
All right.
So now let's just run this.
And we can actually see a little
message for all the
students that got
a good grade.
So there's one more thing
that I wanted to
mention about cursors.
So if you remember, I was
talking about the fact that
when you make the cursor,
it doesn't
actually query the database.
When you make the cursor, you're
actually just creating
an object that describes your
query, and nothing has
actually happened to
retrieve any data.
So it's actually only when you
call a method like .each on
the cursor, or .toArray that
the cursor actually has to
perform the query.
So when you call .each, the
cursor realizes, OK, I don't
have any data.
I actually need to query
the database.
So the cursor sends
its query over,
MongoD sends its response.
And the cursor can start
returning documents, or start
building this array.
But one thing I want to mention
is that the response
from MongoDB is not
necessarily the
entire results set.
So consider a situation where
you have a massive database
with many, many documents, and
you don't actually want to
return the whole set of
documents all at once.
So what actually happens is that
in this response, MongoDB
will return a batch of documents
up to a certain
batch size.
So in this first query, in
response, the cursor gets back
the first batch, can actually
start returning documents
until that batch has run out.
And then once that batch has run
out, the cursor can make
another request, get
the next batch.
And once that batch runs out,
the cursor can make another
request, get the next batch,
and so on, until it reaches
the end of its results set.
So one thing to note here is
that this works very nicely
for a function like .each
because we can actually
process the documents as they
come in, since .each actually
calls its callback for each
document that is retrieved
from the cursor.
However, if you have a function
like toArray, and
you're using that on the cursor,
the callback doesn't
actually get called until
the entire array
is completely built.
Which means you haven't seen the
cursors streaming all this
data, but you're not actually
getting any advantage from the
fact that it's batching
like this.
So this is really meant to make
it easier to stream data
back from the database, rather
than have to wait for the
entire results set before
you can do anything.
So this is something to keep
in mind when you're using
something like toArray.
All right.
So now let's go on
and do our quiz.
So for this quiz, we'll actually
have you complete
some example code.
So this is our example code.
Just like in all our other
examples, we get a reference
to the driver.
We connect.
We check for an error.
And we specify a query
and a callback.
But we're not actually using
this query or this callback.
So your task is to figure out
what to put here to actually
do this query, query for all the
documents with grade 100.
And call this callback.
But notice this callback only
takes a single document and
logs that document.
So it may not be clear here
because this could actually be
an array, technically, but your
quiz is to have a single
document be returned
to this callback.
So your job is to figure out
what to put here such that we
run this query and call
this callback
with a single document.
And once you've figured that
out, fill the answer in this
text box below.