All right, so now we've done
'find', 'find one', and talked
a little bit about how
these queries work.
We've had a basic
introduction.
Let's talk about field
projection.
So, this is an example of find
using field projection.
So the idea behind field
projection is that sometimes
when we're doing a query, we may
be querying on one field.
We may care about certain fields
in the document, like
for example doc.student, but
maybe there are other fields
in the document that we don't
actually care about.
So here what we're doing is the
same query we did before.
Grade, see all the students
with grade equal to 100.
But we also have this
extra thing here.
So this is the projection.
So what we're doing is we're
saying, we want the 'student'
field, so we say 'student' of
one, and we also say we don't
want the _id field.
So if you just have 'student':1
here, then what
that would do it is it would
give you the 'student' field
and the _id field.
The _id field is a
little special.
It doesn't get projected
out by default.
So you actually have to
explicitly say, don't return
the _id field.
So just like before, we do
db.collection('grades').find,
we pass in the query.
We actually pass in the second
argument, the projection.
And just like before we say
toArray(function(err,docs).
So, what I'm doing here
is I'm just iterating
over all the documents.
So this is just a normal
JavaScript array.
JavaScript arrays have
the forEach method.
And I'm passing in a callback,
so this will get called for
each element of the array.
For each element of the array
I'm logging doc, just so we
can see that it's actually
projected.
And doc.student because that's
one of the fields
that we care about--
or actually, the only
field that we care
about in this case.
And we actually don't even need
to have the grade there,
because we know from context
that the student got a good
grade because that was our
query in the first place.
All right, so let's
actually run this.
So we see just like before, Joe
got a good grade, Steve
got a good grade.
But notice here now that when
we log the whole document,
we're only getting a document
back that has student: 'Joe'.
So this is nice because we're
only sending over the wire,
and using the network for things
that we actually care
about, and actually avoiding
sending all that data that we
didn't care about in
the first place.
So that's how you
do projections
using the Node.js driver.
All right, so this is a quiz on
using field projection in
the node.js driver.
So the question is, which of
the following queries will
cause only the 'grade'
field to be returned?
So imagine that in our
collection, 'grades', we have
a bunch of documents they each
have a 'grade' field as well
as an _id field.
So the question is, which of
these lines will cause our
callback to be returned with a
document that only contains a
'grade' field, regardless
of what other
fields were in the document?