All right.
So in this lesson, we'll
actually be importing data
from Reddit.
We're doing this both because
we want to have a more
interesting data set for future
lessons and because we
want to give an example of how
we can use MongoDB to import
and analyze data without
necessarily knowing the full
structure beforehand.
So as a part of this, we'll go
over an example of how to
import data into MongoDB from
an external source using
NodeJS and the NodeJS
driver for MongoDB.
So this is Reddit's
technology page.
And Reddit actually has the
feature where if you
append.JSON at the end, it will
return a JSON object.
So this is what we're going to
be importing into MongoDB.
Okay.
So first we're going curl
this to a file.
Just call it Reddit.JSON.
Let's open Reddit.JSON and we
can actually look a little bit
at the structure.
So I was looking
at this before.
So you can see here that this
one giant JSON object.
And it has a field kind
and it has data.
So actually it looks like data
and children inside the data
subject actually has the list
of the stories we want.
And it looks like for each
story, the data is actually
all the information about
the story itself.
So the way we're going
to actually import
this is using NodeJS.
So let's take a look at that.
So this is an example of how
to import data from an
external source into MongoDB
using NodeJS.
So here we actually have the
Mongo client right here.
Just like before, we
connect to MongoDB.
We also have this
other library.
It's a NodeJS library
for making
requests to other sites.
So here, after we've connected
to MongoDB we then just say
request and give it the Reddit
URL and a callback for when we
receive a response.
So once we get a response from
Reddit, we say okay is it in
error, is it a good
return code.
And if so, we can actually
parse the
body as a JSON object.
So this is basically parsing
our JSON string into the
native JavaScript object.
So after we parse it, the first
thing we do is we say
ojb.data.children, which
we found out was
the list of our stories.
And then just to clean it up a
little bit, we actually map
this array.
So this is an array
of our stories and
arrays have a map function.
And basically what this does is
it applies this function to
every element of the array and
replaces that element with
whatever this function
returns.
So we saw earlier that in our
JSON object for each story,
story.data was actually the
interesting information.
So we just do this
to clean it up.
So we just get an array
of all the stories.
So after that, we have our array
of stories and we can
actually insert the
entire array.
So here we'd just get our
collection that's stored in
the Reddit collection,
insert our stories.
And this function will actually
tell us whether we've
successfully inserted our
stories and actually return
what we inserted it.
So we just log that here.
So we then know that
it succeeded.
So now let's run this.
All right.
So it looked like it completed
successfully.
So just check and actually see
our new Reddit data, let's go
to Mongo and use course and
do db.reddit.find.pretty.
So we can see here, all these
stories are the same as the
ones on our technology homepage
except now that
they're in MongoDB, we can
actually do some interesting
queries on them and ask some
more interesting questions
than we could when they were
just on the front page.
So we could say things like,
which author is posting the
most, how many comments are
there on average, and things
that we couldn't do very easily
when it was just in the
web interface.
So for later examples, we'll
actually use this more
interesting data set rather than
the grades collection we
were using before.
And so the thing to note here
is that we could actually
import this data knowing
very little about the
format of the data.
All we really needed to know is
that the children were in
an array and where to find
that array so we could
actually insert the documents
individually.
and just a little bit
extra for that extra
cleanup that we did.
But other than that, we had
really no idea when we
inserted this what the
structure would be.
We had no idea it would have a
URL, we had no idea it would
have a name field, we had no
idea it would have a numb
comments field.
We just sort of inserted this
into MongoDB and these
documents may be just different
structures, they may
be different sizes,
but it's fine.
So now that they're in MongoDB,
we can ask these
questions, we can make queries
and learn a little bit more
about the structure
of our documents.
So that's what the rest of our
examples will be using.