All right, so now that we've
got our new data set, let's
try to learn a little
bit more about it.
So for our first example,
we'll actually
use the $regex operator.
And what this basically does
is it allows you to build
queries that are regular
expressions.
So let's get right into that.
So let's just say in Mongo,
course, to connect to the
course database directly.
And now, when I looked on the
"Our Technology" homepage, I
saw a lot of posts that
mentioned the NSA.
So let's find all the posts that
have NSA in the title.
So what this query is doing is
we're saying db.reddit.find,
'title', and instead of an exact
match, we're actually
using the $regex operator.
So basically this means that
MongoDB's going to treat this
as a regular expression, and
search anywhere in the title
for the characters 'NSA'.
The title doesn't have to be
this exact string, it just has
to be anywhere in the title.
So that's going to give us
all the documents that
have NSA in the title.
Actually to make this simpler,
let's project out part of it.
So basically here we're going
to project out the ID field
and only include the
title field to make
this easier to read.
All right, so these are the
posts with NSA in the title.
So that's how to do this
from the Mongo show.
Now let's look into how to
do this from node.js.
All right, so here's
our example of
using a regex in node.js.
So pretty much everything
is the same as our other
examples, except here we're
using the $regex operator for
our title, much like the way
we are using #.
So all we have to do is pass on
this query to find, and we
get all the documents
that have NSA
anywhere in the title.
So let's go back here.
And so let's run our app.
All right, so now we run our
application and we can see,
printed out here, titles
of all the posts that
have NSA in the title.
So that's how to use regex in
MongoDB and we could ask
pretty much any question
we want.
We could find all posts with
Microsoft, all posts with
Skype, all posts with
email, and actually
any arbitrary regex.
All right, so this is your
quiz for using the $regex
query selector.
So the quiz is, which of the
following query expressions
would match a document with
Microsoft anywhere in the
'title' field?
Select all that apply.
So here we have four
query selectors.
So you would use these in a find
one query, a find query,
or an update.
And basically these would
specify which documents you
returned from your query.
So your job is to figure out
which of these documents would
actually match a document with
Microsoft anywhere in the
'title' field, meaning that it
would actually be in our
result set.
So you can actually test this by
making some documents with
Microsoft in the 'title' field
and then just putting these
into a find one or find, and
figuring out which ones
actually match.