So now, let's talk
about using dot
notation in MongoDB queries.
So right here, we have a
document from Reddit.
And actually, if you look at it
for some documents, we have
a field called "media" with
another sub-field called
"oembed." And down here,
we have a type "video."
So just for documents that are
videos, we actually have this
nested structure.
So the question is, how do we
find these documents, and how
do we make queries based on
fields in the oembed object,
even though it's nested?
Because if we did a query just
on type, we wouldn't have any
way of knowing whether it was
a type of here in the top
level document.
So let's go and see how
we actually do that.
So this is an example of
using dot notation
with the Node.js driver.
So most of this is the same
as our other examples.
The only thing we've really
changed is our query.
So notice here in our query, we
say media.oembed.type and
with a value of video.
So much like the dollar sign
for the special query
operators, the dot is actually
another special
character in MongoDB.
Dot basically says descend
into nested document.
So in this case, media
is a document, and
we have a dot here.
We say descend into the media
document, look for oembed.
And then we have another
dot saying oembed
is actually a document.
Look for type fields in
the oembed document.
And then check if that field
has a value of video.
So down here, we're actually
going to do a projection.
We're going to remove _id, and
we're only going to get
media.oembed.url.
So this is actually going to
remove all the fields in the
top level that aren't oembed and
remove all the fields in
the oembed document
that aren't URL.
So media.oembed.url
is the only actual
value we'll get back.
So down here, we're
doing other query.
We're actually doing the Reddit
front page, because it
had videos on it.
And we're iterating
the documents,
logging them to console.
Let's just run this, verify
that it works.
So we ran our application, and
turned out the front page only
had one video.
But here it is.
We have the media oembed url.
That's our projection.
All the other fields in the
oembed document and all the
other fields in the media
document and all the other
fields in our top level
document have all been
filtered out.
So this is what we get back.
And note if this field actually
didn't exist, we
would just get back
an empty document.
And also note that for fields
that we queried on that didn't
actually have media.oembed.type,
when we
queried on them in their
application, those just
weren't matched by the query.
So this kind of shows that we
may queries even if we don't
know whether the field will
exist in all the documents.
So this is the quiz
about using dot
notation in a query selector.
Your task for this quiz is to
use dot notation to construct
a query that selects for a
document with a name of
"Steve" in the student's
array.
Put your answer in
the box below.
So to make this more specific,
I have an example of the
document that should
match the query.
So your goal is to find a
query that matches this
document because it's looking
for a name of "Steve" inside
the student's array.
And you'll need to use dot
notation to actually build
this query.