All right, so we're actually
going to talk now about skip,
limit, and sort.
So, the first thing I want to
mention is that these happen
in a very specific order.
So, first we sort, then we
skip, and then we limit.
So, it's important that it
happens in this order, because
if we sorted afterwards, we
might be skipping documents
that we didn't actually
intend to skip.
And through our limit, we might
not get to documents
that we would have otherwise.
So, it's important that
we sort first.
All right, so this is an example
of using skip, limit,
and sort in the Node.js
driver.
So right here, we're
actually using the
grades collection again.
We'll just store that reference
here to make the
code below a little simpler.
And here we get a cursor by
doing grades.find, and we're
actually not being selective,
so this will give us all the
documents in the grades
collection.
So, the first thing we
do is do cursor.skip.
So we skip document,
cursor.limit, and then the
cursor.sort, with the first
argument of the key that we're
sorting on, and the second
argument of the
direction to sort.
So, let's run this.
All right, so we got these
students back.
We've sorted based on the exam
scores, and we see that we
have three 80s and an 85.
So, ascending based on
the exam scores.
So, all the hundreds we saw
are further down the list.
All right, so now let's change
things up a little bit.
So, let's move this limit up
here, and the sort up here,
and do all of these in
different order.
So if we run it again, we see
that we have exactly the same
result that we had before.
So, the reason for this is that
no matter what order you
do the sort, limit, and skip
in, the driver actually
reorders them to make sure they
happen in the correct
order, with the sort first,
the skip second,
and the limit third.
All right, so let's try a
more complicated sort.
So let's comment this
out, uncomment this.
So, what we're trying to do here
is we're trying to sort
on grade first, and then sort
the students alphabetically in
reverse, second.
So, when you have the one here,
it shows that we're in
ascending, which means we're
starting at the low grades,
and increasing.
And here we're sorting in
descending order, so we're
starting actually at the last
names in the alphabet, and
going up from there.
So, let's see how that looks.
All right so the results look
similar, but you can see here
that we're sorting on the grade,
but within all of these
students that got 80, we have
Steve, Jill, Amanda.
So, we're sorting the names in
reverse descending order.
So, one thing I want to note
here is that we sorted the
grades first, and the
names second.
So we didn't sort
alphabetically, and then sort
by the grades inside
those categories.
We actually sorted by the
grades, and then within
documents that had the same
grade, we then sorted by name.
So, the way we determine the
order in which we sort and
which one takes priority
is the order that
they're in this array.
So you notice that grade is
first, which means we sort on
the grade, and then we have
student, which means that
amongst documents that
had the same
grade, we sort by student.
And that's actually why this
here is an array, and not
object, because in the Node.js
driver, if you have an object
here with keys and values, the
fields can actually be
reordered within that
object before they
make it to the database.
For a sort, that would be bad,
because if your object got
reordered without you realizing
it, you may have a
completely different
sort order.
You may be sorting by student
first, and then by grade, just
because your fields got
reordered, whereas arrays
actually do not get reordered.
So we use an array here to make
sure that grade comes
first, and then student comes
second, to tell MongoDB that
we want to sort on grade, then
we wanted to sort on student
amongst grades that
at the same.
All right, so let's look at
one more way to do this.
So, here we actually made a
cursor, and we called the
limit, skip, and sort functions,
but it turns out
that you can actually just
make the cursor with some
starting options when you
do the find query.
So, the first argument to
find is the selector.
The second argument is
the projection, as we
talked about before.
And the third argument can
be an option structure.
So in this option structure, we
have skip of one, which is
equivalent to calling
dot skip of one.
We have limit of four, which is
equivalent to calling limit
of four, and we have sort with
this array here, specifying
how we're sorting based
on grade and student.
If we just wanted to sort on
one key ascending, all we
would need to do is put
a string here with
the name of the key.
And hopefully this makes it even
more clear that the order
in which we call these
doesn't matter.
We're just passing in an object
here, and internally,
MongoDB makes sure that these
happen in the right order.
So let's run that just to make
sure that they're the same.
All right, so here we see
creates are sorted first, and
we've limited to four.
And it looks like exactly the
same result set as we had when
we called the functions
on the cursor.
So, that's how to do skip,
limit, and sort using the
Node.js driver.
All right, so this is the quiz
about skip, limit, and sort.
So, the question is, what are
some ways we can use skip,
limit, and sort in the MongoDB
Node.js driver?
Check all that apply.
So can we include skip, limit,
and sort options in the option
object for find0ne?
Can we pass a sort order as an
argument to find and modify?
Can we call the skip, limit,
and sort of functions on a
cursor before retrieving
any documents?
And can we call the skip, limit,
and sort of functions
on a cursor after retrieving
some documents?
Check all that apply.