All right.
So we've talked a lot about
querying and how to actually
get information out of Mongo
DB, but we haven't really
talked much about how
to manipulate data.
And then we haven't really
talked about write operations.
So as far as those was go, we
have three basic operations.
We have insert, update,
and remove.
So first, we'll talk
about insert.
I think that's the most logical
thing to start with.
Then we'll talk later about
updating and remove.
All right.
So here's another example.
And this is basically showing
inserting a single document
using the Node js driver.
So here we have a
single document,
student Calvin, age six.
And we're looking in the
students collection.
So we have
db.collection.students.insert.
And just insert the document as
the first argument and give
it a call back.
And in our call back, the first
argument is an error.
Second argument is whatever
was inserted.
So we just throw an error if we
found one, otherwise we log
the document that we inserted.
So this is actually going to
be a JavaScript object.
So we call JSON.stringify
to actually get the JSON
representation of this
JavaScript object.
Then we just close
the database.
So this is inserting
a single document.
So let's run that.
So we see successfully
inserted,
student Calvin, age six.
And we see actually this extra
underscore ID field.
So this was automatically
generated
for us by the driver.
And it's actually a unique
key for the document.
So we can actually try
running this again
just to see what happens.
And notice that we insert a
new document, same student
same age, but we actually
generated a new underscore ID
field for the new document
we inserted.
So just to make sure, we can
connect to course database
again, do db. students. find.
And we can actually see the
two documents we inserted.
So let's look at another
example.
So this is another example
of inserting a document.
So the difference here is that
we're actually giving it our
own underscore ID field.
So before we saw that it was
generated but in this case, we
actually are storing meaningful
data there.
We're storing the name
of the student in our
underscore ID field.
So that's really the only
difference here.
But let's actually see what
happens when we run this.
All right, so that worked.
We actually inserted
a document with
ID Calvin, age six.
And notice that the driver
didn't actually generate a new
underscore ID field.
It actually kept the
one we gave it.
So what happens if we try
to insert another one?
So here we get a huge error
actually, because we're
throwing an exception
when we get an error
back from the database.
In this case, we're getting
a Mongo error.
And the message is E11000
duplicate key course.students.
And the duplicate
key is Calvin.
So let's actually go
back into this.
And instead of throwing the
error, we'll just do
console.log error.message
and return db.close.
Now, if we run this, we get a
much nicer error message.
We just get the error instead
of the stack trace.
So it just depends on what
you're looking for.
The error is actually
a built in
JavaScript and Node js object.
So you can actually look in the
documentation for Node js,
and actually some general
JavaScript documentation, to
figure out more about
the error object.
All right.
So those are two examples of
inserting a single document.
But you can actually insert
multiple documents using the
Node js driver.
All right.
So this is an example
of inserting
more than one document.
So here we have four
docs is an array.
And we have a student named
Calvin, age is 16, student
named Susie, age seven.
And we're doing exactly the same
thing, except instead of
inserting a single document here
we're actually inserting
the whole array of documents.
Everything else is completely
identical we're printing out
what be inserted and then
closing the database.
So let's run this.
All right.
So we inserted this array
student Calvin age six,
student Susie age seven.
And actually both documents
had an underscore ID and a
unique underscore ID
generated for them.
So those are some examples of
how to do inserts using the
Mongo DB Node js driver.
All right.
So this is the quiz about
inserting and underscore ID in
the Node js driver.
So we have a section of example
code here, and I'm
just walk through it.
So just like most of our other
examples, we actually open a
database connection.
And what we're doing here is
we're trying to insert these
documents into our collection.
Now, notice we have an
array of documents.
We have two documents here.
And they actually both have an
underscore ID field of George.
Now, this one is uppercase G,
this one is lowercase g,
different ages.
And your task is to figure
out what happens
when we run this code.
And you could actually just copy
and paste this and run it
yourself to verify the answer.
This is actually a multiple
choice question, and we have
the options down here.
So the question is, what
will happen when we
run the above code?
Only one document in the
array will be inserted.
We will get an error because
we are trying to insert an
array of documents instead
of a single document.
We will get a duplicate
key error.
Or both documents will be
inserted successfully.