All right, so now let's
talk about the
node.js driver and updates.
So we're going to talk about
a few different kinds of
updates right now.
So first we'll talk about
replacement updates, where we
actually replace the
entire document.
We'll talk about in place
updates, where you can use
update operators to actually
modify the document without
completely replacing it.
And then we'll talk about
multi-updates, where you can
actually apply these in place
updates to a large number of
documents using a single
operation.
So let's get started.
All right, so here's our example
of updates using
replacement.
So all this up here
is the same.
We connect just like before.
And we have our query
for an assignment.
And here we're doing a find
one just to get the first
document that has homework one
as the value of assignment.
That's 'cause if we're doing a
replacement down here, we need
to actually have our
original document.
So if there's an error,
we throw an error.
If we don't get anything back,
we don't really have anything
to work with for our update.
So we return the error to the
user, close the connection at
the database, and return so
that we don't execute this
code down here with
our no document.
So we'll talk about this
in a little bit.
But coming down here, we
actually have db.collection
grades just like before.
Except now we do .update.
We give it our query, and we
give it the document that we
want to replace the first match
for our query with.
And then down here, we
have a call back.
We can throw an error.
And updated here is the number
of documents that we updated.
So we just print out
a message saying we
successfully updated.
Hopefully, this is going
to be one document.
And then we just close the
connection at the database.
So up here, this is where we
actually are making the
modification.
So we get our document back, and
down here we want to set
the date returned.
So this is just when
we returned the
assignment to the student.
So we set doc date returned
equals new date, all just in
JavaScript.
Nothing MongoDB related here.
And then down here when we do
the update, we pass document
as our replacement.
So it's actually going to be the
same document we got from
the find one, plus the
date returned.
So I want to talk a little
bit about this line here.
So notice that we're actually
doing two separate queries.
So we're doing a query for the
find one, and we're doing a
query for the update.
So we actually may
have other people
connected to our database.
We may have other operations
going on besides just the ones
you see here.
So between these two queries,
things might have changed.
And notice that there's nothing
about find one that
says which document that has
a value of homework one for
assignment we're getting back.
It could be any student for
the document we get back.
But all we really are
selecting on is the
assignment.
So we don't actually have any
guarantee that the document we
get back here is the same
document we update here if we
just use this query
right here.
So what we're doing is we're
saying OK, underscore ID is
unique in the document
that we got back.
So let's just add that to our
query to make sure that the
document that we update is
exactly the same document that
we got back in our find one.
This is important because in our
query we might have gotten
a document with a different
student and then down here
when we update, we're doing a
complete replacement without
checking the old field.
So we might have actually just
updated it and replaced the
old student in a document that
we didn't intend to replace.
All right, so let's run that.
So we see successfully
updated one document.
So now let's take a look.
So I'm going to do
db.grades.find assignment of
homework one.
So notice we get all
our documents back.
And one of them actually has the
date returned set to our
current date.
So that's how to do an update
with replacement.
But notice that we only really
added one field, and we
actually replaced this
entire document.
All the fields happen to be the
same, but maybe it's not
quite as efficient
as we could be.
So let's take a look at
in place updates.
All right, so this is an example
of an in place update.
And note that it's a little bit
simpler just because it
matches more what we're trying
to do right now.
We actually don't need
to do a find one.
We just go straight
to the update.
And as our second argument, this
operator, instead of a
document that we're going to
use to replace our original
document, we actually have
this dollar sign
set operator here.
So what this says is that
we actually query for an
assignment of homework one.
And for the first one we get
back, we actually apply this
operator to that document.
So the result of this will be
that we have our original
document with this additional
field set.
And actually the set operator
will set date returned to the
current date, regardless of
whether it existed in the
original document.
So we just run the update and
we have the call back and we
log a message just
like before.
Updated it as the number of
documents that we updated, so
we hope that says one.
So let's run that.
So we see successfully
updated one document.
So let's actually go into the
course database again and run
db.grades.find assignment
homework one.
So we look here and we see
that we have a list of
documents for homework one, and
now we actually have two
documents with date returned.
So this was the one we updated
before and this is the one we
updated using the
in place update.
And notice that in one case, we
reordered the fields and in
the other case we didn't.
So this demonstrates
that this is
really a different operation.
This one we just saved the
original document.
And this one, we did an in place
update which actually
resulted in the fields coming
back in a different order.
All right, so one issue with
this is that we've only
updated two fields.
And we don't want to have to run
an update for every single
document that we want to
set date returned on.
So let's talk about
multi-updates.
All right, so this is an example
of doing an update on
multiple documents.
So for this example, I'm
actually going to query with
no selector, just select all
the documents in our grades
collection.
And I'm actually just going to
use unset on data returned.
So maybe I made a mistake and I
actually didn't want to set
date returned on any
of these documents.
So this will actually query all
the documents and unset
date returned.
And so what actually makes this
a multi-update is this
options argument.
So the first argument here is
a query, second argument is
what operation to apply, and
the third argument is an
options structure that
specifies what kind
of update it is.
So in this case, it's a
multi-document update.
So just like before, we're
actually printing the number
of documents that we updated.
But we're hoping that
we updated more
than one in this case.
Because we're actually matching
all 16 documents in
the grades collection.
So let's run that.
All right, so we got
successfully updated 16 documents.
So let's take a look.
All right, so we look here and
we actually see all our
documents for homework one.
And notice that none of them
have a date returned field.
And in fact, two of them have
had their fields reordered.
Which shows that MongoDB didn't
actually modify these
documents because it realized
that it was being called with
the unset operator and these
documents actually didn't have
a date returned field
at all, so they
didn't need to be modified.
All right, so that was an
example of updating by
replacing a document, updating
in place using update
operators, and updating
multiple documents.
All right, so here's our quiz.
So this is a little code snippet
very similar to the
ones that we were looking
at in the lectures.
And here we have a query and the
update operator that we're
trying to apply.
So the question is, what happens
when you run the above
code with the given
update operator?
Does it change assignment to
homework two and change date
graded to the current date?
Does it change date graded to
the current state, ignoring
assignment?
Does it replace the document
with a document with only the
date graded and assignment
fields?
Or does it return an error?