All right.
So now let's talk about upserts
using the Node.js driver.
So first we're going to talk
about just upserts, then we're
going to talk about save,
which is actually a wrap
around upsert, which has
slightly different behavior.
So let's get started.
All right, so here's
our example of
using upserts in MongoDB.
So, a lot of this is the same.
We have our query, and
we have our operator.
We have our options.
Here is the arguments to update,
but the difference is
in our options object, we
actually set upserts to true.
So what this means is that it
will try to find a document
that has student Frank,
assignment homework1, and
update it using this operator.
However, if there is no document
matching this query,
then it'll actually just
insert it, and
then apply this update.
Now, right here operator may not
have been the best choice
of variable names, because
there's not actually an
operator in here.
It's actually replacing the
document, or inserting a new
document, so I could have
called it something like
update doc, or new doc.
But I just called it that
because I copied it from the
other one, which is actually
an operator.
So let's run that.
All right.
Successfully upserted
one document.
So if we go into our
shell, all right.
So here we see our new document,
student Frank, with
a grade of 100, and assignment
homework1.
So we see that it applied
the update.
So let's actually get rid of
this, because I actually have
another example that
I want to show you.
So, let's remove Frank, and
see that he's removed.
So now in here, I'm going to
comment out this line, and use
this other operator.
So, this may seem a little
strange, especially in the
context of an upsert where a
document doesn't yet exist.
So, there are two things that I
want to mention about this.
One is that this actually has
exactly the same behavior as
the line here in the context
of this update.
And the reason for that is that
our query is actually
what gets inserted.
So, this document gets inserted
if there's no match.
And then the update operator
is applied.
So in this case, since we just
deleted our student Frank, we
actually will insert this
document, student Frank,
assignment homework1, and then
apply this operator.
So, the other thing I want to
mention is that we're actually
using dollar sign set with an
object that has two different
fields in it.
This is just to show that
a set can be used for
more than one field.
So in our other example,
we just had one.
So this will actually set date
returned to new date, and set
grade to be 100 in place update,
which in this case
doesn't really matter that much,
because we're already
inserting a document.
But this is just to demonstrate
the order in which
this happens.
So, let's take a look.
All right, so here we see
successfully upserted one
document, just like before.
So let's connect to our shell,
and we see exactly the same
thing, just with the fields
in the different order.
So we have student Frank, we
have grade of 100, assignment
homework1, and here we actually
have date returned.
So, I actually forgot to put
date returned in this
document, but you can see that
it was actually set losing our
dollar sign set operator.
So, now let's talk about save.
So, this is an example
of using save
with the Node.js driver.
So, this one will look more
similar to our replacement
update, because it actually
has a similar interface.
So, just like with our
replacement update, we
actually do a find0ne to find
the original document.
And here we actually do doc date
returned equals new date
to add a date to our document.
So, here's the interesting
part.
For the save function, we're
actually providing the doc.
So the question is,
what is the save
function actually doing?
So, the high level answer is
that it takes our document and
actually replaces it in this
case, but what if the document
doesn't exist?
So, what save is really doing
is it's taking the document,
it's checking to see if there's
an underscore ID field
on the document, and if there
isn't an underscore ID field,
save will actually insert a new
document, but if there is
an underscore ID field, save
will assume that we actually
meant to do an upsert.
So it'll take the document and
do an upsert automatically,
with a query on the document's
underscore ID field.
So, this is slightly more
convenient to use than the
replacement update, but in
effect, it's really doing the
same thing.
So, the result of this should
be, in any case, whether the
document existed or not, or
whether it had an underscore
ID field or not, that when this
call returns, we actually
have doc inserted into
our database.
So, let's take a look.
All right, so here we see
successfully saved one document.
Let's connect to our shell
again, do db.grades.find.
Let's just get all the
assignments with homework2.
All right, so we see all the
documents that have an
assignment of homework2, and
down here, we actually have we
have an assignment with
a date returned.
So, notice that actually the
fields weren't reordered on
this one, which seems to show
that save actually has more in
common with our replacement
update.
Since it's really just querying
on the underscore ID
field, in this case, since we
had one, from getting the
document straight from MongoDB,
and doing an upsert
with the entire document.
All right, so now let's
go to a quiz.
So, the question is, assuming
all the necessary variables
are defined, what
is the result of
calling this function?
Is it to attempt to insert the
object and throw an error if
underscore ID is not unique?
Is it to update and replace
the document?
Is it to upsert to insert or
replace the document, or is it
to do an in place update?