All right, so let's talk next
about find and modify in the
Node.js driver.
So first, let's talk a little
bit about what the purpose is
of this function.
So let's look at the
two different ways
you can do an update.
So, one is you do a query, then
you do your update by
replacing the document with
the result of your query.
Now, the problem here, as we saw
before when I was talking
about adding the underscore ID
field to our query, is that
you may do a query, something
may change about the document
we care about, and then by the
time we do the update, the
document is completely
different
from what we saw earlier.
On the other hand, if you do
an in place update and you
want the resulting document
back, you may do an update,
and then a query to get the
resulting document, and just
like before, anything can happen
in this space of time.
You may do the update, the
document may change to be
unrecognizable by the time you
can do a query to take a look
at the document's contents.
So that's the reason for
find and modify.
Find and modify atomically
updates
and returns the document.
In fact, we can actually specify
whether we want to
return the new document
or the old document.
So, let's look at an example.
All right, so this is an example
of when find and
modify would be useful.
So, at a high level, what we're
trying to do here is
we're trying to increment to
counter and get the value of
the counter immediately after we
increment it, before anyone
had a chance to also increment
the value or change its value.
And so for this, we really do
need find and modify, because
if we tried to do an update
and then a find to get new
value of the counter, other
clients could've also called
update and incremented
our counter.
So by the time we find it, we
don't actually get the value
that it had immediately
after we updated it.
So, this is an example of when
we would need find and modify.
So, let's go over the pieces
of this example.
So first, we connect, just
like in all our other
examples, and once we have our
database connection, we call
db.collection, and then get
the counters collection.
Then once we have a reference to
the counters collection, we
call find and modify.
So, this takes four arguments.
So let's go through
them one by one.
So, first there's our query,
and this is very similar to
the query selector
in an update.
It just tells us
which documents
we're looking to modify.
So in this case, we're looking
for documents that have a name
of comments.
Now, the next argument
is sort.
So it may seem a little strange
that we're doing a
sort here, because find and
modify actually only modifies
and returns a single document,
so why would
we need a sort here?
So, the reason we need a sort
is, consider the situation
where this query is not
specific enough.
So, in this example, maybe we
have two documents that have
the name field with the
value of comments.
So in that case, we don't really
know which document
we're going to update, because
find and modify will only
update the first document that
it finds, and then return that
in our result.
So the sort order gives us a way
to get more control over
which document we're updating.
So in this example, if two
documents had a name of
comments, we could sort by some
other field, and that
would give us more control
over which document that
matched name comments
would get updated.
In this case, I'm just assuming
only one document has
a name of comments, so I'm not
even passing in the sort,
because I'm not worried
about this happening.
Next argument is our operator,
and this is actually exactly
the same as an update
operator.
It just specifies what operation
we're trying to do
on the document.
So in this case, we're
trying to increment
our counter by one.
Now, the next argument is the
options argument, and the
option that we're passing
in is new colon true.
And what that's saying is that
we want the new document to be
returned from find and modify.
So find and modify can return
either the document before we
perform this update, or
the document after
we perform the update.
And so we actually want the new
value of the counter, so
we're passing new true.
So after find and modify
completes, the driver will
call our call back with the
resulting document.
So, because we've passed new
true here, the resulting
document will be the new
document after we've
incremented our counter.
So, we're checking for
an error here.
We're making sure that we
actually found a document, and
if not, we log a message here.
And if we did find a document,
we log number of comments, and
then the number of comments
in our counter.
Then after that, we close
the database connection.
So, let's actually run this
and see what happens.
All right, so this is our
find and modify example.
So, we ran it.
We see no counter found
for comments.
So in our example, we actually
checked to see if document was
null, and if it is null, it
means that there was no
document that matched
our query selector.
So let's actually add a counter
for comments, so that
when we run our app, it actually
finds something,
updates it, and we can
see the result.
All right, so connect to the
course database, and let's do
db.counters.insert.
And let's do name of comments.
I'm just not putting quotes
around the name.
That's legal JavaScript,
but not strict JSON.
All right, so now we've inserted
a new counter.
Notice that we didn't give it
a counter field, and the
reason for that is because,
similar to the dollar sign set
operator, if the field doesn't
exist, increment will actually
create it, and assume that
the value was zero.
So let's run our application
again.
Now we see number of
comments, one.
We run again, we see number
of comments, two.
If we run it again, we see
number of comments, three.
All right, so that's an example
of using find and
modify in Node.js, and the
important thing about this is
that no two applications running
at the same time would
have a conflict here, because
find and modify atomically
finds, modifies, and returns
the document.
So you couldn't have two
applications that both get the
same value for this counter,
because the counter is
incremented and returned
atomically.
All right, so this is the quiz
on find and modify in the
Node.js driver.
So the question is, which of
the following calls to find
and modify will add the dropped
field to the homework
document with the lowest grade,
and call the given call
back with the resulting
document?
So note that there are three
parts to this question.
The first part is is our call
to find and modify actually
matching the homework document
with the lowest grade?
The second part is is it
successfully adding the
dropped field to the homework?
And the third part is will it
actually call the call back
with the resulting document, or
will it call the call back
with the old version
of the document?
So your task is to select the
correct answer out of these
options provided.