All right, so this is the
answer to the quiz about
findAndModify in the
Node js Driver.
So this line here is the
answer to our quiz.
So first we have an empty
query selector--
this means we're matching
all documents.
The reason we have to do this is
that we don't actually know
which grade is the lowest, so we
can't actually make a query
that eliminates any
of our documents.
Next, we have a sort on grade
increasing, so this is what
allows us to actually match
the correct document.
It means that we're matching
all documents.
But the first document we get
back will be the lowest,
because we're sorting
on grade increasing.
Next, we have this dollar sign
set operator just like in the
update, where we set
dropped to true.
Finally, we pass an options
object with new set to true to
tell findAndModify to call the
callback with the resulting
document rather than with
the old document.