All right, so this is the answer
to the quiz about using
remove in the Node.js driver.
So first of all, this last one
wouldn't be guaranteed to
remove all the documents because
there may be some
documents for which the x
field does not exist.
And those documents would not
match this query specifier and
therefore not be removed.
This next one would remove all
the documents because we're
passing an empty query
specifier.
This one's a little bit
trickier because we're
actually passing a specifier
for x not in, and then this
empty array.
This is a little bit of a subtle
point, but it turns out
that every document would
match the query selector
because documents that have an
x field are guaranteed to not
be in the survey, as well
as documents that do
not have an x field.
Now, this top one may seem a
little strange because we're
not actually passing a query
specifier at all.
That's actually supported
by the driver.
So what the driver actually
does is, it will check the
types of its arguments to figure
out what you actually
passed in and act accordingly.
And in this case, passing just
a call back and no query
selector is the same as passing
a query selector that
matches every document.