All right.
So now we're going to get to our
course project, "Building
a Blog on Node.js." We'll
have most of the
blog written for you.
And your job will be to fill in
specific queries to MongoDB
that update the necessary
collections or read data from
the collections that we
use to populate the
pages on the blog.
Right now, I'll just show you
the user interface so you get
a sense of what the finished
product is going to look like.
We'll go to a terminal just
to show you to do this.
If you look in here, we have
our blog project files.
This is our main application.
This is the application we're
actually going to run.
And here we have a "routes"
directory.
And this actually has all
our routes for express.
Down here, we have sessions,
users, and posts.
These actually correspond
to our three
collections for the blog.
These contain the code that
you're actually going to be
modifying to complete
this project.
The first thing we want
to do is run our app.
And you notice, we actually are
looking for a module that
we don't have installed.
If you notice up here, we
actually don't have a node
modules folder.
But we do have a package.json
folder.
So let's just type
"NPM install" to
install all of our modules.
All right.
So we installed all
our dependencies.
Let's just run our
application.
All right.
Express server listening
on port 3,000.
So let's take a look at
what our finished
blog should look like.
Let's go to local host 3,000.
And we're at our blog.
This is our home page.
There's nothing on
it right now.
Let's actually log in so we
can create a new post.
Let's create a username "test,"
password "test." And
we have no such user.
So let's hit the back button
here and actually sign up.
Here's our sign up page.
Let's create a username "test"
with a password of "test," and
verify test with test
example.com as our email.
All right.
So now we're logged in.
We can actually go to
our blog homepage.
It's not very interesting
because it doesn't really have
any posts on it.
So let's go create a new post.
Let's call it "first." This
is the first post.
Now down here we
have our tags.
And we can say first, comma,
post, comma, blog.
So now let's submit that.
And we are actually
specifically
at our first post.
And we can go to
the blog home.
This shows all the posts.
We just have one right now.
And notice we actually have
zero comments on the post.
So let's add a comment
to our post--
first comment on first post.
So we submit.
Now our post has a comment.
Let's create another post.
And let's give it some
of the same tags.
Let's give it post, blog
tags, and submit that.
Now we just see second, because
we're specifically on
the page to view the
second post.
So let's go back to our home.
And now we can see we have both
our first, second post.
First post has one comment.
Second post has zero comments.
And they have some
tags in common.
The next thing we can do is
actually see all posts for a
specific tag.
Right now we just have two, so
it's not terribly interesting.
But basically what this is
showing is all the posts with
the tag "post." Actually if we
click here on "first," we just
see all the post with the
tag "first," which
is just this one.
And finally, we have
a log-out page.
And once we log out, we can
still see our posts.
So this is actually visible to
people not logged in, but we
actually can't create
a new post.
So that's the basic
functionality of our blog.
This is just so you get a sense
of the finished product
would look like when you're
working on your application.
Hopefully that's enough of an
introduction so that you know
what the blog should do
and how it should
work when it's finished.