So let's talk a little bit more
about building a blog on
Node.js, and a little bit about
some of the stencil code
that we're going to
provide to you.
And hopefully by the end of
this, you'll understand
exactly which parts of it you'll
need to fill in, which
parts are just there as
part of the example.
So basic overview of the
application is that there's an
app.js file which is basically
our main, connects to MongoDB.
And it actually includes
everything
in the routes folder.
So in the routes folder, we
actually have the routes for
express that we register, and
describe what we do when the
user navigates to
a certain URL.
So for example, if the user
navigates to login, in the
routes folder, that's where we
have the code to actually
handle what to do when
the user connects
to the login route.
Now, at certain points, the
routes actually need to access
data from MongoDB.
And the code for that is
contained in sessions.js,
posts.js, and users.js.
So down here, these are the
three files that actually have
the code for interacting with
MongoDB, and they correspond
to the sessions collection, the
posts collection, and the
users collection respectively.
So that's the basic layout
of our application.
So let's actually take
a look at the code.
All right.
So if we look at all the files
we have here, we have our
app.js, we have our
routes, post.js,
sessions.js, users.js.
And then our views, which
contain our HTML files which
are just swig templates that
we render to the user.
So let's start with app.js, just
to start with our main
entry point.
All right.
So this is app.js.
Notice that we require
express, we require
consolidate, MongoDB,
and ./routes.
So I'll talk a little bit
about this after I get
through this file.
This is the way I'm specifying
a subdirectory.
And we'll look a little
bit more at how
this works in a second.
If we go down to the main body
of our code, basically, this
is our whole application.
So we connect to MongoDB.
We register our templating
engine
just like we did before.
We have some middleware for
express, because we need to
access cookies and post
variables in our blog.
And then we delegate, actually,
to our routes.
So we pass in the app
and a connection
to this routes object.
And then we just listen
on port 3000,
print out a nice message.
So if we go back up here to the
top of the file, we see
that we have routes equals
require ./routes.
So what's going on here?
So what this is doing is it's
telling Node.js that we want
to include a local file.
This isn't actually a module
because if we didn't have the
dot slash, it would actually
look for a module named
routes, just give an error
message saying, module routes
not found, unless we happen
to have a module
installed for that.
So let's actually look more into
this directory and see
what we can find.
So notice that routes is
actually a directory.
So when we get that require
statement for ./routes, we're
actually saying to include
this directory.
What that's doing is it's
actually including this
index.js file.
So there are more details
about how the require
statement works, and how it
looks up different files, but
this is just an example of what
happens when you use a
local path and include
a directory.
So let's just take a look
index.js before we look at the
rest of our routes.
So this is index.js.
And this is the function that's
getting called when we
call the routes function.
Because at the top of our app
we had routes equals require
./routes, and then we were just
calling that function.
So here we're saying
module.exports = exports =
function, that takes an app
and connect to database.
And here we have some helpers
that I'll show in a bit that
actually have the content of the
code that we use to deal
with the routes.
So if we look down here, we can
see that we're registering
all our routes.
We do app.get/ and we
actually pass in
what's actually a function.
So our contentHandler has
a function called
displayMainPage.
We're passing that to slash
route for express to use when
a user request slash.
You see something
similar here.
We have contentHandler.d
isplayMainPageByTag,
contentHandler.d
isplayPostByPermaLink.
Just all sorts of helper
functions that we register
with the routes.
So this is basically our top
level of the routes file where
we're just matching routes
with the work
that we need to do.
So now if we look down here,
we can see that we have all
these things to handle
our session.
So here we have get for the
login form, we have the post
for the login form, the get for
the signup form, the post
for the signup form, when the
user actually submits the
signup form.
We have the Welcome page,
we have the Logout page.
That's all managed by
the sessionHandler.
And then we just register
some error handling
middleware down here.
As one last small thing I want
to mention, we actually have
our own middleware here.
So we're saying,
app.use(sessionH
andler.isLoggedInMiddleware).
I use session So this is
actually to keep the code a
little bit nicer because every
page basically needs to know
whether the user's logged in,
because the content of the
page may be different.
So this just contains that
duplicate code as middleware,
and it gets called every single
time no matter what
route we're going to match.
So this middleware will get
called, and because we
register all our routes
afterwards, it'll get called
before our routes.
All right.
So we've looked a little bit
about how we match the routes
to the work that
we need to do.
Let's actually look at the
content of that work, and soon
we'll get to the actual database
operations and the
point of this homework.
But I just wanted to really give
a good overview of what
this application is doing so
you don't feel like there's
magic happening under
the covers.
And the good news is that for
the part you have to write,
you don't have to really
use this stencil code.
You just have to use MongoDB.
And so you don't really have to
know how this works, it's
just going to call
your functions.
So if we go all the way back up
to the top, we can see that
we have our SessionHandler,
ContentHandler, ErrorHandler.
That's ./session, ./content,
and ./error.
So let's look again in
our routes directory.
We see we have content.js,
session.js, and error.js.
So notice we did include the
.js, but no js actually tries
to append .js extension and
see if the file exists.
So notice that this behavior is
different for a directory,
where it actually looks in
routes/index.js because it
didn't find a routes.js
in the top level.