So now, let's take a
look at session.js.
All right.
So notice at the top here, we
actually include these helpers
and dot dot slash users and
dot dot slash sessions.
So we'll talk about that
in a little bit.
But basically, these are
our objects that we
use to access MongoDB.
So it's a users data access
object and a sessions data
access object.
So this kind of tells us that
the session handler really
needs access to the users
collection and the sessions
collection.
So let's take a look at a little
bit about how it's
using this.
So I'm going to skip over a lot
of this because it's not
as important for the homework.
But I just want to sort of
cover how this fits in.
So down here we'll say users
and sessions as our data
access objects.
And all of our functions are
implemented using these objects.
So we actually have, this is
logged in malware uses the
sessions object and calls the
get username function, which
I'll show you when we actually
look at the sessions.js file.
So if we look down here we
have this other function,
handle login request, takes a
username and a password as
post variables, so request dot
body because we registered the
body parser.
It will be populated with
post variables.
So we have request dot body dot
username, request dot body
dot password.
These are post variables that
we registered in our form.
So here we just call users
dot validate login.
So just like with the sessions
object, users is a data access
object with methods that
interact with MongoDB.
So here we have a validate
login function takes the
username and password and
returns our user.
So you don't really need to
know how this works, but I
just wanted to show you how
these pieces fit together.
So this is our sessions
data access object.
It takes a connected
database object.
Down here it uses it to connect
to the sessions
collection.
And we have this.startSession
and other functions attached
to this, so that what this will
return is an object that
actually has all of these
helper functions.
So let's take a look at how some
of these are implemented.
So this is the sessions
data access
object on start session.
And it's a function that takes
a username and a callback.
So notice this isn't doing
any validation.
The job of the sessions
collection is actually just to
keep track of users so they
don't have to login on every
single page.
So we do a bunch of stuff here
to generate the session ID.
We create a session document,
and we just insert it.
So now, if we go down here we
see the end session function.
So all this does is finds, based
on the session ID, which
is stored in the cookie--
I didn't cover that.
But that's how this function
gets called.
--and we just remove the
session document.
So this is basically when
a user logs out, we call
sessions data access object
dot end session.
All right.
So now, this is the sessions
data access
object dot get username.
So this takes a session ID,
which we've also got from the
cookie, and a callback.
So if we look down here, we
actually do sessions dot find
one, ID, session ID.
And we check to see if we've
gotten a session.
So if we do get a session, we
return session.username.
And this will call back
into the code
that's using this function.
So I haven't talked about this
much, but notice the way we
implement this function is
also with a callback.
So just like a lot of the other
functions we use, like
find one, this one is going to
be used with a callback and is
asynchronous.