All right, so this is the
answer to homework 2-1.
So if you remember, we just
looked at our weather_data.csv
file, saw that it had
a header line.
So when we type "mongoimport,"
we want to pass --type csv
--headerline.
And now we actually have to
specify what database and what
collection that we're
importing our
weather data into.
Now here we specify the file.
We run this command, connect
to the local host.
And we imported almost 3,000
objects from this
weather_data CSV file.
So now if we enter the Mongo
shell and use the weather
database, and we type
db.data.findOne, because
that's collection we actually
put this in, you can see we
have our weather document.
So this is part one, so
we've successfully
imported our data.
So now let's talk
about part two.
So that's the analysis
portion.
So the assignment was to figure
out the state that had
the lowest temperature recorded
when the wind
direction was coming from the
West, meaning that the wind
direction was between
180 and 360.
So let's talk that through.
So we can do db.data.find.
And we want our wind direction
to be greater than 180 and
less than 360.
And then we want to sort
on temperature.
And we want to sort increasing
so that the document we get
back is going to be the
lowest temperature.
And let's limit that to one
for simplicity, and let's
pretty print it.
All right, so this
is our document.
It's New Mexico.
And we have a wind
direction of 260.
That's coming from the West
between 180 and 360.
And we have a temperature
is zero.
So this is the lowest recorded
temperature for that month
when the wind was coming
from the West.
So that's the answer
to homework 2-1.