All right, so this is the answer
video for homework 2-2.
And if you remember, the way
we recommended that you do
this assignment is by sorting
first by state, and then by
temperature.
So this means that we can
actually just look at the
first document for each
state and know that
is the month high.
So the assignment for homework
2-2 was to set the month high
field to true in the document
with the highest temperature
and do that for each
state individually.
So let's take a look
at the solution.
All right, so this is our
solution for homework 2-2.
And our goal is to find the
highest temperature for each
state and set a month high
field to true in the
corresponding document.
So what we're doing here
is, we are just
connecting to MongoDB.
And we're doing a find with an
empty query selector and then
sorting on state, ascending,
doesn't matter whether it's a
ascending or descending, and
temperature descending.
So this is going to give us a
cursor with this sort order.
And we're calling toArray on
that cursor to get all the
documents back in one big
array all at once.
And then, down here, we're
iterating our documents array.
And we're actually looking
for these month highs.
So the way we do that is, we
set state originally to an
empty string.
And then we start iterating
our documents.
And when we see that state is
not equal to docs i state, we
push our months i, and
then we set state
equal to docs i state.
So this will only get triggered
when we're where
either at the beginning of our
iteration and state was empty,
or we're transitioning
to a new state.
So we're actually adding to this
month highs array all the
documents that are at the
beginning of a transition to a
new state, which happened to
be the documents with the
highest temperature because
we're sorting on temperature
decreasing within each state.
So that's how we get
the month highs.
But let's take a look at how
we actually update these
documents that correspond to
our month highs with the
months highs fields,
which was the
assignment for this homework.
All right, so down here we have
the loop that's updating
our month high documents.
So note that we actually could
have used a multi update for
this example because we could
have actually constructed a
query with the dollar
sign in operator.
But I wanted to show an
example of how the
asynchronous model
is different from
the synchronous model.
So in this case, we have our
array of month highs.
And it's going to be an array
of four documents because we
have four different states.
We're actually just iterating
through this loop and calling
.update on every month high.
And for every month high, we
pass the dollar sign set with
month high to true as
the update operator.
And you may notice that we're
doing a little bit of extra
work here because we're actually
counting the number
of times this callback
has been called.
And the reason we're doing that
is because we shouldn't
actually close the database
connection until we have a
response from all
of our updates.
So what we're doing here is,
we're setting the number of
callbacks to zero.
And we're making sure that the
number of callbacks we've had
so far is not yet equal
to month_highs.length.
And then once it is equal to
month_highs.length, we can
safely close the database
connection, knowing that we
received responses for all the
updates that we sent out.
So this may seem like we're
doing some extra work here
because of the asynchronous
model.
And in some ways, that's
actually true.
If we were doing this
synchronously, we could just
say db.collection.update,
db.collection.update,
db.collection.update, and then
db.close at the end, knowing
that, by the time we got that
line of code, all of our
updates had returned.
But the problem with that is,
that means we have to wait for
a response from each update
before we can
send the next one.
So we're doing each update
synchronously and waiting for
the full round trip, whereas
here, what we're doing,
actually, is we're actually
just sending this update,
returning immediately, and
continuing the next iteration
of our loop.
So in each iteration, all we do
is really send the update.
And we don't actually have to
wait for the full round trip
to the server.
So this allows us to fire off
the four updates and get the
responses as they come back,
rather than waiting for each
update to complete before
sending the next one.
So that's one of the advantages
of the asynchronous
model, is that we could
dispatch a lot of I/O
operations in parallel without
having to wait for the results
of each one to dispatch
the next one.
So for this little bit of extra
work, and little bit of
extra overhead, we actually have
a lot of parallelism in
terms of our I/O operations
in a single thread.
All right so that's the answer
to homework 2-2.
So we're finding the
month highs by
iterating through our documents.
And then we're updating all of
our documents with the month
high field using the $set
update operator.