All right, so let's talk
about homework 2-2.
So in the last homework, you
imported a weather data set.
And in this homework, we are
actually going to ask you to
do a little bit more complicated
analysis on this
data set using the
Node.js driver.
So let's take a look
at our assignment.
All right, so your assignment
for this homework is to write
a program that finds the
document with the highest
recorded temperature for each
state, then add a month high
field for that document, setting
its value to true.
Use the weather data set that
you imported in homework 2.1.
And a hint, which I'll go over,
is that if you select
all the weather documents, and
you sort by state and then by
temperature, you can iterate the
documents and know that,
when the state changes, you've
reached the highest
temperature for that state.
So we have four states that
we have data for.
And we have a month's worth of
data for each state, which
means that you should end up
setting the month high field
on four different documents.
All right, so the way we
recommend you do this homework
assignment is to construct
a query where you
first sort by state.
And then you sort by
temperature, decreasing.
So what that gives us is a sort
order such that when we
change states, we know that that
document has the highest
temperature for that state
because within a state the
temperature is sort
of decreasing.
So basically, here, we started
iterating our results set.
And we know that this document
is going to have the highest
temperature because we sort it
by temperature decreasing
within this state.
As we iterate further, we get
down, and we see that we've
transitioned to state two, which
means we know that this
document now has the highest
temperature for this state.
So that's how we recommend you
complete homework 2-2.