All right.
So here's the answer to the
homework assignment.
This is the answer
to homework 2-3.
So just to recap, your
assignment was to fill in the
user's data access objects
so that sign-up and
login work in our blog.
So let's take a look at
the finished code.
All right.
So the first function we
had to implement was
the add user function.
This is actually called from
the sign-up formula blog.
So we get a user name, password
and email from the
user that wants to sign up.
So if we look down here, we can
see our to-do for homework
2-3 and the finished result.
So your job was to insert the
user document into the
collection, effectively adding
the new user because all our
other validation functions
depend on this user document
and check the result.
If there is no error, you
just can log that you've
inserted a new user.
You call back with null and the
result's actually an array
of documents that
we've inserted.
So we call back here
with result zero.
And if there was an error, we'd
call back the error and a
null result.
All right.
So the next function
was validate login.
So this is the one
with this giant
validate user dock function.
But if we go down here, you can
see that the code that you
actually need to implement
this is just one line.
So we just do users.findOne, the
ID of user name and just
pass it the validate
user dock function.
So this will handle all the
validation for us and call our
original call back that was
passed in to this overall
function with whatever error
occurred or the user document,
if we found it.
So that's the answer
to homework 2-3.