All right, so let's talk
about blog performance.
So for this homework assignment
you're going to be
making the blog fast and adding
indexes so that the
queries that the blog
uses look at as few
documents as possible.
So the first page you need to
make fast is this page.
So this is the main page of the
blog and this is actually
loading the 10 most
recent comments.
So we actually provided
with this homework an
example data set.
And this is the Gettysburg
Address, this is the Bill of
Rights, Declaration of
Independence, and a lot of
duplicates, and we generated
a bunch of
random tags for these.
So Gettysburg Address doesn't
really have a lot to do with
Freon, but we generated a lot of
random tags so that you can
have an example data
set to play with.
And we ask you to import this
data set so that we can use
our validation script to make
sure that you're not actually
looking at too many documents.
All right, so for this first
page we're loading the 10 most
recent documents.
So that means you have to figure
out a way to make the
query for the 10 most recent
documents in the post
collections fast.
And you can reference the code
or you can just think about
what kind of query that would be
and make an index for that.
So the next thing that we want
to make fast is looking at the
posts by a given tag.
So in this case we are looking
for the tag of pasta and we're
looking at all the posts that
are tagged pasta, so it turns
out Gettysburg Address has
a lot to do with pasta.
If we click Freon, we get
all the posts that
are tagged with Freon.
And your assignment is to make
this fast, so what this is
doing is it's still sorting
based on the date but it's
also filtering by the tag.
So it's only returning
the documents that
have a given tag.
So your job is to make this page
fast by adding an index
for that query.
So finally the last one you need
to make fast is the page
for a specific post.
So in this case we have a single
post, the Gettysburg
Address, with the list
of comments.
And we have the permalink up
here, so this is the URL that
we use to access this post.
So your job is to make the query
that finds a single post
by given permalink fast.
So that's your assignment
for homework 4.3.
It's to make the blog fast by
adding indexes to these pages.
So the front page which looks
for all posts but only returns
the most recent 10, the page
that filters posts based on
tag and also still sorts by the
most recent date, and then
the page to just show
a single post.
So those are the pages that you
need to make fast in this
assignment.
So for this assignment you
can reference posts.js.
And posts.js actually
has all the queries
that we need to optimize.
So getPosts is the function
that's called from the front
page, and it's doing a find
for all documents and then
sorting on date, and then
limiting by the number we
provide which is actually 10.
It's passed in from
somewhere else.
And down here we have
getPostsByTag, so this is used
to display all the posts
through a given tag.
And note we also limit by the
number and we're also sorting
by the date.
Finally we have
getPostByPermalink and this is
for getting a single post.
And we're just doing a findOne
here and querying for the
permalink which should
actually be unique.
All right, so those are the
three queries in the code that
you need to optimize.
You can go back and
reference those.
And are validate script will
actually basically be running
these queries and making
sure that we don't
scan too many documents.