All right.
So now let's talk about
connecting to a replica set in
the Node.js driver.
So just to recap, of replica
set is a collection of
multiple MongoD nodes that
communicate with each other
and try to keep a most up to
date copy of the entire data
set as they possibly can.
They should be as close to
duplicates as possible.
We went for high availability
and automatic failover.
So the way you deal with this
in an application is through
the driver.
And actually, the driver is
going to do a lot of the work
for you in terms of managing
the connections and keeping
track of which nodes are up and
which node is the primary.
So, for this lesson, we'll
cover how to start a
connection to a replica sat
in the Node.js driver.
So the way you start a
connection is you actually
give the driver a connection
string just like before with
the host names and ports of
the nodes that you want to
connect to.
So in this case, we could give
host names and ports of all
three nodes.
You can actually give them in a
comma separated list, or you
could just give the host name
and port of a single node and
the driver would automatically
detect that it's a replica set
and discover the rest
of the nodes.
So let's just take a quick look
at an example of how this
will work in a real
application.
So before we start, we need
to start our three
node replica set.
So here I'm going to start my
first replica set node.
I'm going to give it the port
30001, dbpath data dbrs1.
So that one started.
So let's start our next node.
I'm going to start this one on
port 30002, still in local
host, give it a different
data path.
And finally, we'll start our
third node of our replica set,
give it port 30003, dbpath
different from the other two.
All right.
So before we can actually
connect we need to configure
our replica set.
So let's connect to local host
30001, and you see we aren't
actually a replica set yet.
I try rs.status we
get an error.
So let's run rs.initiate
to actually
start our replica set.
All right.
So we're starting up our
new replica set.
The next thing we want
to do is actually add
the other two nodes.
This is just sort of a recap
of the other lessons, but I
just want to go over
it one more time.
So I happen to know that the
host name is education.local,
and the port is 30002
on the first node.
And then for the next one, the
port is 30003, same host name.
So now we've added all our
nodes to our replica set.
If we clear this, look at
rs.status, we can see that we
have all of our notes
connected.
We have our primary and we
have the two secondaries
starting up.
All right.
So we've started our
replica set.
Now let's take a look at the
application that we're going
to use to connect to
our replica set
using the Node.js driver.
So this may look familiar.
We still use our Mongo
client, we're still
using the same functions.
The only real difference here
is that instead of giving a
single host name and port, we're
actually giving a comma
separated list.
I'm using this plus operator
to concatenate the strings
just so we don't have one long
string wrapping around.
The window is a little
too small.
But, basically, all I'm doing is
passing a single connection
string to the connect function,
giving it a call
back exactly the same way as
I did with a single node.
And I'm just giving this comma
separated list of replica set
members instead.
Note that I could also just give
one member, and it would
still be able to connect
assuming that member was up.
If that member was not up, then
it would not be able to
find the rest.
So down here we're using this
DB object just like we did
with the single node,
connecting the repl
connection, inserting
a document.
And down here we're connecting
to the repl collection and
we're finding one document.
And we should find the document
that we just inserted.
Then we're logging the document
and closing the database.
So let's just run
this example.
All right.
So we just ran our example,
and you can see that we've
answered our document and we've
found it successfully.
And this was all connected
to a replica set.
So what actually happened here
is that we gave it the
connection string with the three
replica set nodes, the
driver automatically connected,
figured out which
one is the primary, figured out
what the secondaries were,
got the status of everything,
figured out exactly where to
send our write and our read.
And all of that happened behind
the scenes so that our
application didn't have to
have any of the logic of
dealing with all the complexity
of the added
connections.
So that's how you connect to
a replica set in Node.js.
All right.
So this is the quiz for
connecting to a replica set
from the Node.js driver.
The question is, if you leave a
replica set node out of the
seedlist within the driver,
what will happen?
Is it, the missing node will
not be used by the
application?
Is it, the missing node will be
discovered as long as you
list at least one valid node?
Is it, the missing node
will be used for
reads but not for writes?
Or is it, the missing node will
be used for writes but
not for reads?