All right so the answer is--
The write weights forever.
Now this may not be true if
you have a timeout, but
basically, the driver
keeps waiting for a
response from the nodes.
Doesn't throw an error and the
server doesn't throw an error.
It's just waiting to meet the
requirements that you set in
the write concern.
It does not go to as many nodes
as possible then return
success because that would not
be meeting the constraints
that we specified.
It would be writing to fewer
nodes than we specified in the
write concern, which means that
we would be getting the
wrong idea about where
our data actually is.
So that's the answer to the quiz
about node concern and
the node.js driver.