All right.
So now let's talk about
Write Concern
and the node.js driver.
So, basically, Write Concern
is a way we can specify the
behavior of writes in MongoDB.
So, for example, the default
Write Concern is one--
so this would be represented as
W:1 is to send a write to
the primary and return success
to the user once the primary
acknowledges the write.
In other situations we may not
care about an acknowledgement,
so we do a Write Concern
of zero.
And in that case, the driver
immediately returns success
after it sends out the operation
and returns to the
application without receiving
a response.
Use case for this maybe if
you're just streaming tons of
click data or some data where
it's so massive that if you
lost a write it wouldn't be a
big deal, and throughput is
the most important factor.
You can also specify a Write
Concern of two to say, only
return success if the primary
and a secondary--
at least one secondary
acknowledges the write.
So the driver will not return
success to the application
until two nodes have
been written to.
Same thing applies for three.
Three nodes have to acknowledge
that they've
received the write
before the driver
returns with the success.
And so on and so on for other
numbers, depending on the
number of nodes you have in
your set, and how many you
want to make sure they've
received the write.
You can also do a Write
Concern of j.
And what this does is it says,
write to the primary's journal
before you return success.
So this ensures that the data
will be persisted because we
have a write head journal
in MongoDB.
So if we've written to the
journal, we know that no
matter what happens--
if we crash--
we can replay the journal and
bring it back to the point
where the write had
been applied.
So W:j ensures that it has been
persisted to disk before
the driver would return
success to the user
application.
Finally, we have W majority.
Basically this makes sure that
we've written to a majority of
the nodes in our set before we
return success to the user.
So these are some
of the different
levels of Write Concern.
There's also the idea of tagged
Write Concern where you
can specify a custom Write
Concern that involves writing
to two different data
centers or a certain
subset of the nodes.
But that's a more advanced
topic so we'll just be
covering these basic Write
Concerns and how to use them
in the Node.js driver.
So let's just take a look
at a quick example.
All right.
So this is our example of using
Write Concern in the
Node.js driver.
Note that most of this
is the same.
We still have the same
connection stream, we still
are calling the same collection
functions, but we
have this extra thing
at the end.
So we have this question
mark, w=1.
And this looks a lot like the
syntax we use for putting get
variables in a URL, and it
happens to be the same syntax
we use in a MongoDB connection
string to specify additional
parameters for our connection.
So in this case, we're saying,
connect to MongoDB and set the
Write Concern for all
operations on this
connection to one.
And what that means is, for
operations where we don't
specify an explicit Write
Concern, it'll take the Write
Concern of our connection
and do the write
using that Write Concern.
So this insert will do a Write
Concern of 1, because we
didn't explicitly specify it.
And this insert, because we
actually pass in this options
object with w of 2, we'll have
a Write Concern of 2,
overriding the Write Concern
for the overall connection.
So this is the basic idea
of Write Concern.
You can do it here for the whole
connection, or you can
do it in individual operations
if you pass in the right
options object.
You can also pass a j here
or a majority string.
Same thing here.
And this is where you would also
pass in tags if you're
doing a tagged Write Concern.
So let's just run
this example.
What we expect is to see
inserting this document then
this document and logging them
both to the console.
All right.
So this is our example,
the Write Concern.
This was the document that we
inserted that had a Write
Concern of 1 in the
insert call.
This is the document we inserted
that had a Write
Concern of 2 in the
insert call.
Since all three nodes of our
replica set are up, we had no
problems getting responses from
two of the nodes, or even
the primary just to make these
two writes succeed.
So that's an example of
using Write Concern
in the Node.js driver.
All right.
So let's take a quiz about
using Write Concern.
All right.
So this quiz is about the Write
Concern in a Node.js
application.
And I recommend you try this
out in the driver.
It's a good way to experiment
with a Write Concern and
verify that it's actually
working as you expect.
So the question is, what happens
if we specify a Write
Concern larger than the
number of nodes we
currently have out?
Is it, the write
waits forever?
Is it, the driver
throws an error?
Is it, the server
Or is it, the write goes to as
many nodes as possible, then
the driver returns success?
So check the correct answer.