So now let's talk about
read preference
in the node.js driver.
So by default, all reads
from the driver
will go to the primary.
But you can actually configure
the behavior of your reads if
it fits your application.
So you can configure your reads
to go to the primary,
which is the default.
You can configure your reads
to only go to secondaries.
You can configure your reads to
prefer the primary or the
secondary, which means if one or
the other is not available,
it'll try the other.
So for example, if it's
primary-preferred and there's
no primary, then it will fall
back and use the secondary.
But it'll use a primary
if it's present.
And you can also specify to
use the nearest node.
You can also use tagged read
preferences to configure
precisely which nodes you
want the reads to go to.
But that's a more advanced topic
and also outside the
scope of this course.
So we're just going to talk
about the basic read
preferences, which is primary,
secondary, primary-preferred,
secondary-preferred,
and nearest.
So let's look at an example of
using read preference in the
node.js driver.
All right.
So what we're doing here is,
like before, we're specifying
a connection string.
And just like with the write
concern, after the connection
string, we have these things
that look like Get variables.
And here we have a variable
readPreference, and we're
setting it to be secondary.
So that means on this
connection, all the reads will
go to a secondary unless
we specify otherwise.
So the first thing we're doing
is doing an Insert here just
to insert this one document
in our collection.
And then we're doing a Find
down here in this
findDocument function.
So if we go down to the
bottom, we have this
findDocument function, which
we're calling down here.
A findDocument function is
registering itself to be
called in one second.
So we'll call it, it'll send
out a Find, and register
itself to be called again
in one second.
So the result of this is we'll
do a findOne every second for
a document with the field,
x, and a value of 1.
So in this case, we're actually
overriding the read
preference of the connection.
So this is another way to
specify the read preference.
This is in our option
object to our query.
So here we're specifying read
preference, which we imported
above, .PRIMARY.
So this is just an enum with
all of our different read
preferences.
I can glance at that.
So we have read preference
is just from the
MongoDB package again.
And we just get that enum out
so that down here we can use
ReadPreference.PRIMARY and
specify that we actually want
this Find to go to a primary,
which is the default.
But we're overriding it for
this connection because we
specified secondary.
So I'll show both ways.
I'll show with overriding this,
and then I'll show an
example of what happens when
we just use the read
preference of the secondary that
we set on the connection.
So let's run this application
now and see what happens in a
failover scenario.
All right.
So we're running our
application.
And you can see we're doing a
Find every second, pretty much
returning the same document
each time.
We see different
documents here,
because I ran this before.
So now let's cause a failover.
We'll connect to local
host 30,001.
And we see that it's
a secondary.
So what we want to do now is
do rs.status to figure out
where our primary is
so we can kill it.
All right.
So it turns out our primary is
on education.local 30,002.
So education.local is my actual
host name but I know
it's on my local machine, so
I can just use local host.
Now I connect.
I see it's the primary.
Use Admin and then
db.shutdownServer.
So now this primary's been shut
down, we have a failover.
And let's see what our
application is doing.
So we see that the Finds are
actually not returning any
results yet.
So they're still dispatching.
And now we see all the
results come back.
So if we look at what happened
here, we see that we were
dispatching all these Finds but
there was no primary to
actually take the query.
So the driver just buffered
them as it did before in a
normal failover scenario
with writes.
So this is the default behavior,
and this is because
we're setting read preference
at primary
in our option object.
So now let's go back and look
at our application.
And let's not override
the read preference.
Let's allow these reads to go
to a secondary and see what
happens in a failover
situation.
This is just to show that this
is actually changing the
behavior, because sometimes
it's hard to see what's
actually happening.
You know, you can't really look
and say, look, the writes
are going to the secondary.
You actually have to do some
kind of experiment like this
to really get a sense
of what's going on.
So here I've removed
the option object.
So now this findOne will be
using the read preference that
we set for the connection,
which is read
preference of a secondary.
So now we've run our
application.
You see it has pretty much the
same behavior as before.
But now let's see what happens
in a failover situation.
So now let's connect to
local host 30,001.
We see that it's the primary,
so we don't have to check.
We see in the prompt
that it's primary.
I don't have to look
for that primary.
So let's use Admin, and let's
shut down this server.
So now we've shut down our
primary, let's take a look at
our application.
So from what I can see, it looks
pretty much unaffected.
We're still dispatching
a Find every second.
I highlight it there to
make it easier to see.
Basically, it's unaffected by
the failover, because we still
have secondaries that can
service our reads even though
we've completely shut down
our primary server.
And in fact, because I shut
down these other two, we
actually only have
one node up.
So we definitely do not have
a primary up, but this
application is still happily
reading from the secondary.
So you may ask why don't we
just do this all the time?
Why don't we just always read
from the secondary?
And the answer is that the
guarantees you get from
reading from a secondary aren't
the same as the ones
you get from reading
from a primary.
So if we go back to
our picture--
because the writes are going to
the primary, it takes some
time for them to propagate to
the secondaries, which means
if your reads are coming from
the secondaries, you may not
have the most up-to-date
copy of the data.
So the same application may have
just done a write, and
they read a different result
that's out of date.
So that's the danger of
doing secondary reads.
It does have some benefits, but
you have to really think
carefully about whether it's
OK for your application to
have that kind of eventual
consistency.
All right.
So that's how you deal
with read preference
in the node.js driver.
So let's take a look
at a quiz.
All right.
So the quiz is, you can
configure your application via
the drivers to read from
secondary nodes within a
replica set.
What are the reasons that you
might not want to do that?
Check all that apply.
Is it, if your write traffic is
significantly greater than
your read traffic, you may
overwhelm the secondary, which
must process all the writes
as well as the reads?
Replication lag can result.
Is it, you may not
read what you
previously wrote to MongoDB?
Is it, if the secondary hardware
has insufficient
memory to keep the read
working set in memory,
directing reads to it will
likely slow it down?
Or is it, reading from a
secondary prevents it from
being promoted to primary?
So check all that apply.