All right, so the answer to the
quiz is these first three.
So this one and this one are
basically saying that reading
from the secondary, adds more
load to the secondary.
And you have to be aware of the
consequences that may have
to your entire system.
If your secondary becomes
overloaded, it may lag behind
the primary, because it can't
actually keep up and replicate
the data while also servicing
other reads.
Another issue is you may not
read what you just wrote,
because the secondary may not
have the time to catch up.
And then last one, which is
similar to the first answer,
is just that it may slow down
the secondary, if the
secondary isn't powerful
enough to keep up
with all the reads.