So for this homework, we asked
you to set up a three-node
replica set.
And at a high level, basically,
what you need to do
is start three normal MongoDs.
But you have to give it the
replica set command line
option, giving it the name
of the replica set.
You give it the data path, just
like you would a normal
MongoD, except each MongoD in
this replica set needs a
different dbpath.
And it needs to be on a
different port, because we're
running these all
on local host.
So once you have these three
nodes up, you actually have to
make sure they're all
connected and
all configured properly.
So down here, we give you
instructions on how to set up
the configuration for the set.
This is our example
configuration.
We have our host name
and our port.
And we have IDs for the members
and then the ID for
the replica set name.
So you could also do rs.initiate
with no arguments
to automatically create an empty
configuration, and then
just do rs.add to add
the other members.
But in this case, we set up our
configuration all up front
and call rs.initiate
with our config.
So at this point, you could
type rs.status to see the
state of our replica set and,
right at the end, run
validate.js, just like you did
in all the other homework
assignments that had
validation scripts.
You may have to install the
dependencies, but this will
confirm that it works.
So I'll show you
how to do that.
All right.
So let's step through
setting up this
three-node replica set.
So this is a script that
I wrote to set
up the three nodes.
This is the first phase of
setting up our replica set.
First, we're moving the data
directories, so you need to be
careful here.
But I know these are all
basically empty.
Here, I make the new
directories.
And here, I'm just starting
the three MongoDs.
So I give it the replica set
name, different log files and
different data paths, different
ports, small files
to not use too much disk space,
and fork to basically
run this in the background.
So this command will run, start
up MongoD, then continue
on to the next line, start up
MongoD, then continue on to
the next line, start up MongoD,
rather than starting a
MongoD and running it
in the foreground.
So this is the script to
set up the three nodes.
So first, let's make sure we
don't accidentally have any
nodes running on the system.
So I'm going to kill
all the MongoD.
So it looks like it didn't
have any running.
So I can do bash set_up.sh.
So this is actually a good
example of one of the issues
you would run into setting
up a replica set.
So I think this is good
to talk through
what's happening here.
So you see, we have mkdir:
/data/rs1: Permission denied.
And what that basically means is
we don't have permission to
create those directories.
So there are two ways we
can deal with this.
One is we can change the
permissions on /data.
And the other is we can just
pick a new dbpath, which is
what I'll do in this case, just
so I don't have to change
permissions on files
on my system.
But if you wanted to change the
permissions on this, you
would use the chmod command.
And you actually have to have
root permissions to use this
to change certain directory
permissions.
But for now, let's just
edit our script.
And instead of running in
/data/rs1, let's do ./data,
just so we're running locally
in our home directory.
We don't have to worry about
permission issues.
All right.
So now we have our data
paths locally.
We have permission to edit
these files and make
directories here and do
whatever we want.
So this shouldn't be an issue.
All right.
So now we run our
setup script.
And we see that all of
these are forked.
So let's actually tail this
log, see if we started
successfully.
And we see that it started.
And it's waiting for
connections.
But it hasn't yet
been configured.
We see this empty config
issue right here.
So now we have our three nodes
running, let's try to
configure them.
So for that, I have a script
that I'm going to run through
the Mongo shell.
So let's take a look.
So all this is doing is creating
a JSON object for our
config with our replica
set name and our
members, hosts and ports.
This is just what was
in the assignment.
And we're just going to run this
as a script in the Mongo
shell and see what happens.
So if we do mongo configure.js,
so the shell
just ran our configure script.
So now let's actually try to
connect to our replica set and
see how it looks.
So we see we're connected
to a secondary.
So if we do rs.status, we
can actually see the
status of all our nodes.
We see this one is
in secondary.
This one is still starting
up, in STARTUP2 phase.
This one is in state UNKNOWN.
So it looks like it's waiting
for a primary
to do initial sync.
So that's kind of interesting.
So let's just run in
this a few times.
We see that this is the primary,
which is a good sign.
And we see these other two
nodes are secondaries.
So we have our replica
set fully set up.
So now that everything's
set up, how do you
prove that it's working?
So I'm just going to run the
validation script real quick
to show how that works and
then show you the code.
So here we have package.json
validate.js.
So we do npm install, install
the dependencies for our
validation script.
All right.
So now we can do node
validate.js.
And we see that we validated
successfully.
We have a three-node
replica set set up.
It has the correct output
and rs.status.
And the local.system.replset
collection has all the nodes
that we were looking for.
And here, you see the code to
enter in the assignment.
All right.
So that's the answer to homework
6-5 on how to set up
a three-node replica set.