All right, so now we're going
to talk about using hints in
the MongoDB Node.js driver.
So before we do that, we're
actually going to cover using
Explain in the driver.
So this is a way to get
information about what index
we used and information about
our query and the performance
of the query.
So let's take a look
at an example
All right, so this is our
example of using Explain in
the MongoDB Node.js driver.
So what we have here is we have
a find query looking for
x equals 2.
And we're making a cursor
out of that.
And then we're calling
cursor.explain.
So you remember that we would
call cursor.each,
cursor.toArray, and then we'd
get our documents back.
Instead, we're doing
cursor.explain.
So remember that this
line doesn't
actually run the query.
This line just sort of builds
our cursor object, which
describes what our query is.
This line is actually
running our query.
And we're choosing to run
it in the explain mode.
So note that after this we can't
actually do cursor.each.
We can't actually do
cursor.toArray, because we've
already run the query.
So doing the explain actually
runs the query, because it
really has to run it in order
to get the actual statistics
about how the query was run.
So it takes one call back, which
gets an error object and
the explain output.
So all we do in this function
is we just log the explain
output and then close the
database connection.
All right, so let's run our
example using explain and
querying on x equals 2.
All right, so this is our output
of our application.
Notice, we get a
document back.
But this is not a
document that is
actually in our database.
This is a document describing
how the query was run.
And we can see up here
that the cursor we
used BtreeCursor x_1.
So before this video, I inserted
a few documents.
And I actually made
an index on x.
So this says that we used
our index on x.
And then this 1 specifies
the sort order.
So this is actually a really
good query, because n, which
is the number of documents that
we actually got as the
result of our query, is equal
to n scanned objects and n
scanned, which is just the
number of documents and index
entries we actually
had to look at.
So down here, we see some other
statistics about our query.
But for now, let's ignore that
and move on to hinting in the
Node.js MongoDB driver.
So let's go back
to our example.
All right, so here's
our example again.
So I'm going to change
a little bit.
I'm going to actually add some
more parameters to Find.
And then we'll discuss that.
All right, so I added two more
parameters to Find here.
I Actually added an empty
projection operator.
So we don't actually want to
project our documents.
And then I added this
options object.
And in the options object,
I added a hint.
And the hint value
is $natural:1.
So what this is saying is, for
this query, our hint is that
we want to not use an index.
$natural is actually
a special keyword.
It just says, don't use an
index for this query.
So this will actually construct
our cursor.
And then when we call .explain,
it's going to be
called with these options.
And we should see a difference
in our explain output.
So let's actually run this
and see what we get.
All right, so we're running our
application with our hint
to not use an index.
So let's see what
that looks like.
All right, so down here we
have our explain output.
And we can see that the
cursor changed.
So instead of what we saw
before, which was the B-tree
cursor on x, we actually see
we're using a Basic cursor.
So this is just the name for a
cursor that scans the entire
collection and looks
at every document.
So down here we can
see that n is 1.
So our result set is
still the same.
We still get one
document back.
One document matches
x equals 2.
But we actually see that we have
an increase in number of
scanned objects and n scanned.
So we only actually have six
documents in this collection.
So we actually had to look at
every single document before
we could actually return the
result of our query.
All right, so MongoDB actually
listened to our hint.
And that's good for not
using an index at all.
But let's actually talk about
using a different index.
All right, so I'm going to
change this a little bit so we
can use a different index.
All right, so here I changed the
$natural to underscore ID.
So this is just saying, if
there's an index on underscore
ID, use that for this query.
So you could put
anything here.
You could put y, z.
If you have an index on y or
z, MongoDB will use that
instead of trying to determine
which index to use itself.
So let's run this and actually
see what results we get.
All right, so this is
hinting to use the
underscore ID index.
So we have some interesting
results here.
So like the first query we
ran, we see we're using a
B-tree cursor.
We're actually using a B-tree
cursor on underscore ID.
So MongoDB listened to our hint,
which is great, but we
have kind of a problem here.
So here we have n is 1, so our
result is 1 as always.
But down here, we actually have
n scanned and n-scanned
object is 6, just like
when we weren't using
any index at all.
So because our query had nothing
to do with underscore
ID, scanning doesn't
help us at all.
The speed of an index lies in
its ability to rule out ranges
of documents.
And if we're using an index
underscore ID and looking for
a document that matches x equals
2, we can't actually
rule out anything.
And we still have to look at
every single document.
So
This is actually even worse,
in some ways, than the
$natural, because we not only
have to read all these
documents, but we actually
have to bring in the
underscore ID index and
scan the entire index.
So there's even an added layer
of overhead there.
So this is just an example of
why you need to be careful
when using the hint and why you
need to really understand
when a query can efficiently
use an index.
Because otherwise, you'll get in
this situation where you're
trying to use an index and
MongoDB faithfully listens but
performs a very inefficient
query.
So this example seems very
simple, because we're querying
on x and we're looking
at underscore ID.
It's intuitive that we can't
really use this index.
There may be situations where
intuitively you'd think an
index would work well for a
query, but because of the way
indexes are structured and
because of the way they're
laid out, it might not actually
be very efficient.
So it's important to be very
aware, if you're hinting,
exactly how indexes work
and whether it
will actually be faster.
And I would actually recommend,
if you're planning
on using a hint in an
application, to just run
Explain to make sure that the
query is actually faster by
looking at n and n scanned.
All right, so that's hinting
and Explain in the MongoDB
Node.js driver.