All right.
So this is the solution
for homework 4.3.
So let's look at our posts.js
file again.
So if you remember, we have
these three functions.
We have getPosts, getPostsByTag,
and then down
here we have
getPostsByPermaLink.
So these three functions are
what we want to optimize.
So we actually want
to optimize this
query sorting by date.
We want to optimize this query
looking for the given tag and
then sorting by date.
And then we want to optimize
this query, which is doing a
look up by PermaLink.
So for this example, we're just
going to use the mongo
Shell to show how to make
these queries fast.
So if we open mongo blog--
so what this is doing is it's
telling MongoDB that we want
to connect to the
blog database.
And first let's do
show tables--
see what connections we
have in our blog.
So we have posts, we have
system.indexes.
So we haven't actually made any
users, so we don't have a
users collection or a sessions
collection yet.
But if I had created a user
before showing this example,
we would see the users
collection and then the
sessions collection here.
But right now we just see
the posts collection.
So the first thing we want to
do is try the query for our
front page, where we show the
10 most recent blog posts.
So let's do that.
All right.
So this is the query to find the
10 most recent blog posts.
So we're not filtering on
anything, we are sorting by
date decreasing, and limiting
to 10 documents.
So let's see what
that looks like.
All right.
So these are our 10 most
recent blog posts.
So our query worked, but
let's actually find
out how fast it was.
So if we go back and run the
scan, we can do .explain on
the end and see how fast
our query was.
So notice here that n is 10, but
nscannedObjects is 1,000.
So we have to scan 1,000
documents before we could
return just our latest
10 posts.
So how can we make
this faster?
So the key here is that
an index is sorted.
So we can actually just create
an index on date, and we could
create an index that's either
increasing or decreasing--
it doesn't actually matter--
and MongoDB will know to use
that index to find only the 10
documents it needs.
So the key to this is that an
index is sorted, and we're
trying to sort on date, so if
we have an index on date,
MongoDB can just start iterating
our index from the
very beginning or from the very
end, depending on whether
our index is increasing or
decreasing, and get all the
posts back in the
correct order.
So let's do that.
Let's create our new index,
and then look at the new
explain output.
So here we're going to create
an index on date decreasing
for our query where we're
looking for all posts and
sorting on date.
All right.
So we just created our index.
So now let's go back to our
query, and run the explain and
see what the result is.
So this is a much
better result.
You see we have n is 10,
nscannedObjects is 10,
nscanned is 10, and we're using
the BtreeCursor instead
of the BasicCursor.
So this is much, much faster.
We have basically sped up this
query by 100 times, which is
pretty significant.
So that's how to make the front
page of the blog fast.
We need the index on date
decreasing or increasing-- it
doesn't matter--
If you made it increasing,
MongoDB would know to start
from the end, as opposed
to the beginning.
But I just showed decreasing
for this example.
So now the next thing we want
to do is make the page with
the tags fast.
So for this we're going to use
our same query, but instead of
getting all the documents and
getting the 10 most recent
documents, we're just going to
get the documents for a given
tag, and then get the 10
most recent documents.
So let's actually look for
tags 'freon.' All right.
So this is interesting.
So we've wrote our query
filtering by the tags, and
then sorting by date decreasing,
and it seems like
we've used a BtreeCursor,
which shows that we've
actually used an index
for this query--
which at first seems good.
But then we look at the detail,
and we see that we
only returned seven objects
but still had
to scan 1,000 objects.
So this is kind of a problem.
We're still using the cursor,
but it's not actually giving
us the advantage we're
looking for.
So why is that the case?
Why did we have to scan 1,000
documents before we could
return our seven?
So the key is that, even though
we're iterating the
index and getting these dates
back in a sorted order, we
don't actually know until we've
looked at every document
that we found all the documents
with a tag of
'freon.' And in this case, we're
returning 10 documents,
and there were only seven.
So we had to look through every
document before we could
be sure that we have found all
documents with a tag of
'freon.' So how do we
solve this problem?
Well, what we really need to
do is we need to create an
index on tags, so that MongoDB
can actually use the index and
eliminate parts of
the results set.
So again, it's the fact that the
index is sorted, and when
MongoDB looks at an index, it
can say, I'm looking for the
tag of 'freon,' everything past
this point is later in
the alphabet than g, so I can
eliminate that, and just focus
on this part, and then repeat
that process until it gets all
the way to the bottom.
So basically we need to create
an index on tags to make sure
that MongoDB can actually
efficiently look up tags, in
addition to sorting on date.
But we can't just create
an index on tags.
We actually should include date
in the index as well, so
that every time we find a
section of the index with the
tag we're looking for, we know
that that's already sorted.
But let's actually just try
creating an index just on tags
and see what happens.
All right.
So now we're creating
an index on tags.
So we've created our index.
And now we can go back and run
this query again looking for
the tags of 'freon' and
sorting by the date
decreasing.
So we run this query, and we
see that we have n is 7,
nscannedObjects is 7,
and this looks good.
We've actually used our tags
index to efficiently find just
the documents we're
looking for.
And then afterwards we can
just sort by date.
So I was mentioning before that
we should include the
date in the index, and
the reason for
that isn't clear here.
In this case, we only returned
seven documents, and there are
only seven documents with the
tag of 'freon' in our whole
collection.
So it didn't really matter that
it wasn't sorted, because
we only returned those
documents.
And we are able to just get the
full result set, and then
sort it, and then
return it back.
So I want to show the issue here
by limiting to something
less than 7.
So let's run this same query,
but limit to 5,
and then call .explain.
So this shows why an index on
just tags isn't quite the
optimal index for this query.
So in this case, we're only
looking for five documents,
but there are seven documents
in our whole collection with
the tag of 'freon.' So we
see that n is 5 and
nscannedObjects is 7.
So the issue here is that we
find all the documents that
have a tag of 'freon'
very efficiently.
We can find all of those
documents efficiently, but
when we find them, they're not
actually already sorted,
because we don't have date
included in the index.
So we find our documents with
tags of 'freon,' and we
actually have to retrieve all of
those documents, then sort
them, then return the five
latest documents out of the
seven that we retrieved.
So this doesn't seem like a big
problem now, but imagine
we had 500 documents with the
tag of 'freon.' In that case,
we'd only be looking
for five documents.
We'd have to get all 500
documents with the tag of
'freon,' sort them all, just
to return the five that are
the most recent documents.
So how can we improve this?
Well, the answer is that we want
to include the date in
our index, so that not only
does the index allow us to
efficiently look up the
documents with tags of
'freon,' but when we find
them, they're already in
sorted order.
So what we want to do is we
want to edit this index,
making it a compound index, and
include date in the index.
So we have an index on tags.
Now let's make it also
on date decreasing.
So we've added our new index.
Now let's run that query that
wasn't quite optimal.
All right.
So these are the results
for our query.
And notice that before, n was
5 and nscannedObjects was 7.
Now in this case, both of these
are 5, because by the
time we found our documents with
the tag of 'freon,' they
were already sorted, so we could
just return the first
five that we found, because
we know they're already
sorted in the index.
So that's the key is that the
index basically is sorting on
the keys that we give it.
So that index that we had tags
of 1 and the date of negative
1 basically gives us a structure
that sorted first on
tags, and then when we
have duplicate tags--
like the seven documents
with 'freon'--
then we sort that section
based on date.
So it's all about the sort
order, and this is something
to think about.
But this is the most optimal
index for the Tags page.
All right, so let's go to our
last index, and that is
finding a single blog post.
So to find a single blog post,
let's just get an example
document and get
its permaLink.
So I'm going to do
db.posts.findOne().permaLink.
And let me just assign this to
a variable, make it easier.
So now we do db.posts.findOne(),
and we're
looking for a document with
a permaLink of permaLink.
And note that neither of these
have quotes around them.
This may seem a little strange
at first, but key names with
no quotes are allowed
in JavaScript--
and just mean the key name-- but
the field name is actually
this variable here.
So this is a little confusing,
because I use the same name
here, but this is
the key name--
it's just allowed in JavaScript
that the key name
is unquoted--
and this is the actual
variable, permaLink.
So that's going to
be this here--
it's going to be right here.
So if we do db.posts.findOne(),
let's just do .title.
All right.
We've found the title
of our document.
So now let's see how
fast this query is.
Let's run the explain output.
All right.
So this doesn't work,
actually.
We do findOne() on permaLink,
and then we try to do
.explain, and we see
we get a TypeError.
So the reason for this is that
the findOne() is actually a
nice wrapper that returns us an
object instead of a cursor,
and the .explain method
is actually a
method of the cursor.
So to fix this, let's
actually do a
find, and then do .explain.
So this should also only find
out one document, because
we're looking based
on the permaLink.
All right.
So this is our explain output.
You see we're using a
BasicCursor, and we're only
returning one document, but the
number of objects we had
to scan is 1,000.
So we had to scan 1,000
documents--
every single document
in our collection--
before we could return
a single blog post.
And this could completely take
down your application.
So our query is actually
scanning 1,000 times more
documents than it needs
to to get the results.
So this one's pretty
straightforward.
We're looking based on
permaLink, so we want an index
on permaLink to make
this query fast.
So let's just do that.
All right.
So we've made our index
on permaLink.
So now let's run that query
and see how fast it is.
All right.
So this looks like a
big improvement.
So we're doing fine for this one
document, and we see that
we're using a BtreeCursor
here.
So we're actually
using an index.
And n is 1, nscannedObjects
is 1.
So we only had to look
at one document to
return this blog page.
And so the blog is now much
faster than it was before.
All right.
So that's the answer to homework
4.3, and how to use
indexes to speed up queries
for the blog application
you've been working with
for this course.