All right, so this is our first
query operators using
the Node.js driver.
So we're going to talk
about using less
than or greater than.
So, let's look at an example.
All right, so just like before
we connect to MongoDB using
the connection string.
We have our callback here,
gets a [? connect to ?]
database.
And we have our query, we have
our find, here we're doing
.each over all the documents,
and logging the documents to
the console.
So the thing that we're going
to focus on here is this.
So dollar sign is actually
reserved character in MongoDB,
and it tells MongoDB, hey,
this is a query operator,
among other things.
So if you do dollar sign,
greater than, you're saying,
OK, this is a query operator.
It means I'm looking
for anything
greater than this value.
So here we have "grade." So
before we were looking for all
the students that had
grade of 100.
But what if you wanted to look
for all the grades in a range,
or some other function
of the grade.
So, that's what the greater
than, less than operators
allow us to do.
So, here we have our grade,
and instead of a value, we
actually gave it an object.
And in this object we have the
greater than or less than
operators, so the object
is actually
sort of a query specifier.
We have special requirements
for this query, and the
requirement is that we're
looking for anything greater
than 80 and less than 95.
And just to add a little more
in here, we also have
'student' 'Joe,' just to show
that we can specify more than
one field in our query.
Here we just say, 'student' has
to exactly match 'Joe,'
and 'grade' can actually
be a range.
So you can have really any
combination of exact matches
and query operators when you're
doing your query.
We could actually in here say
'assignment' as well.
So, let's take a look
at what we get back.
So let's run our application.
And we see, we get only
documents back that have
'student' of 'Joe,' and we get
all of his assignments that
had grades between 80 and 95.
So that's an example of using
less than or greater in the
Node.js driver.
So here's a quiz.
This is just to see if you're
paying attention.
This is a quiz about using the
dollar sign greater than, and
dollar sign less
than operators.
So here we just connect, we
check our errors, and then we
do a find with our query and use
each function, iterate the
documents and print them
to the console.
So your job is to actually
define this query object to
get all the documents with the
grade between 69 and 80.
So we want to find all of
the Cs in this class.
So when you figure that out,
come down here and enter it
into the text box.