All right, so this is the
answer to the quiz
about using a $regex.
And it actually turns out that
this is the only query
specifier that would actually
match a document with
Microsoft anywhere
in the title.
And the reason this matches is
because, by default, $regex is
just saying, look for this
pattern anywhere in the string
that we're matching against.
So this one doesn't match
because we're using a $regex
at the top level.
We're not actually querying
against the title field.
And this is actually an invalid
query because we're
trying to use $regex at the
top level and not actually
using it as a specifier for
any particular field.
Down here, the reason this
doesn't match is because we
have this carrot at the front.
And what that means is that
this is anchored at the
beginning of the string, so this
would only match titles
that have Microsoft
at the beginning.
And this one doesn't match
because we're not actually
using $regex.
We're just matching
against Microsoft.
So this would only match
documents that have a title
that exactly matches
Microsoft.
All right, so that's the
answer to the quiz.