All right, so this is the answer
to the quiz about skip
limit and sort.
So we can include skip limit
and sort options in the
options object for
find and findOne.
We can pass a sort order as an
argument to find and modify.
We can call the skip limit and
sort functions on a cursor
before retrieving
any documents.
But we cannot call the skip
limit and sort functions on a
cursor after retrieving
some documents.
Now, the reason for this is
that, once we've already
started our query,
we've already
retrieved some documents.
And we've already made a
commitment to the original
skip limit and sort.
So consider an example where you
returned a few documents,
and then you called sort.
It would be kind of a problem
because the first few
documents you got back may or
may not have been sorted, and
you're asking MongoDB to sort
the rest of the results set,
which is not actually supported
and, really, isn't
usually what you would want.
And the same issue applies
to skip and limit.
We may return some documents
that we should have skipped,
or we may have returned more
documents than the limit by
the time that we actually tried
to set these parameters
on the cursor after retrieving
the documents.