All right, so we've talked about
finding documents in
various combinations.
We've talked about updating
documents.
We've talked about inserting
So now let's talk about
deleting documents.
So for that, we have
a small example.
All right, so this is an example
of using remove in
Node.js driver.
So here we have a query.
We're looking for all documents
that have an
assignment of homework three.
And all we have to do
is pass that as the
first argument to remove.
So what this will do is it will
just delete all documents
that match this query.
So maybe homework three
was a bad assignment.
We just want to delete
all those documents.
And the second argument to
remove is a call back that
takes an error and a number
for how many documents we
actually removed.
So here we logged into the
console, successfully removed,
and then the number of
documents, documents.
All right, so let's run that.
So we actually get--
successfully
removed four documents.
So if we run it again,
we see successfully
removed zero documents.
So the first time we ran this,
we matched all documents that
had an assignment of
homework three.
We removed them so that when we
ran it again, we actually
had no matches and removed
no documents.
All right, so that's how you
remove documents in MongoDB.
So now you know the complete set
of CRUD operations using
the Node.js MongoDB driver.
All right, so this is the quiz
about using remove in the
Node.js driver.
So the question is, which of
the following remove calls
would definitely remove all
the documents in the
collection "foo," regardless
of its contents.
Check all that apply.
You can assume that call back
is a function defined
elsewhere that we expect
to be called when
the remove call completes.