So now let's talk about
homework 2-1.
So let's take a look at what's
in this directory.
So we have a homework
question here.
But when you extract, you'll
see this file called
weather_data.csv.
And your assignment will be to
import and analyze this file.
Let's actually take a
look at this file.
So notice here that at
the top, we have
all of these headers.
And then down here,
we have our data.
So this is actually important
and something you want to pay
attention to when you're
using mongoimport.
So if we look at mongoimport,
you can see there's this
option, --headerline.
And basically it says that
the first line in
input file is a header.
So this is nice, because it'll
make sure that we've set all
our fields correctly and put the
values in with the correct
field names.
So just to repeat that, you want
to add --headerline when
you import the CSV file
using mongoimport.
And you also want to
use --type.csv.
So to take a look at our
homework question, part one is
to import weather_data.csv
using mongoimport.
And then part two we ask you
a data analysis question.
So this is just some background,
so you kind of
know what the data is
you're dealing with.
But the thing to focus on is
that your assignment is to
figure out the state that
recorded the lowest
temperature when the wind was
coming from the west.
So what that means is the
wind direction field is
between 180 and 360.
So just restate this, you want
to find the state that had the
lowest recorded temperature in
a document that had the wind
direction field between
180 and 360.
So that's homework 2-1.