So I'm in the homework 2-3
directory, and I'll show you
the code here because it
actually doesn't include the
parts that you need to write
for the assignment.
So if we go into our blog
directory, look at the files
inside, notice we don't have
a node modules directory.
So the first thing we actually
want to do is just install the
dependencies, so let's just
take care of that.
All right.
So now we've installed our
modules, so next we'll try to
run it and see what happens.
So looks like we have our
express server listening on
port 3,000 just like
we did before.
Let's go to our blog, see if
we notice anything wrong.
So the first thing we'll do is
refresh the page, and notice
our old posts are still there.
And let's just try to login.
All right.
So it looks like we
can't login--
validateLogin Not
Yet Implemented.
All right.
So that's weird.
Well, let's see if we can sign
up with a different user.
All right.
So that's weird--
addUser Not Yet Implemented.
So we actually can't login and
can't sign up, and therefore,
we can't actually make posts,
so it's not actually that
useful right now.
So that's actually going to be
your assignment and I'll
actually go into the
code and show you
exactly where that is.
And notice we have some scary
looking stack choices here.
That's actually just part of our
error handling code, which
I'll also talk about.
So finally, we'll get to the
code that you have to
implement for the homework
this week.
So this is in users.js.
So remember when we went to
the blog, there were a few
pages that returned errors and
said Not Yet Implemented.
So one of them was validate
user and the
other one was add user.
So let's take a look
at these functions.
All right.
So this is the addUser function
of the user's data
access object.
So this takes a username,
a password, email, and a
callback and actually creates a
new user, so this is what's
going to be called from
our sign up page.
So here we're doing some
generation of the password
hash, we're creating a new
document for this user with
username and the password hash,
possibly adding the
email, but we're not actually
doing anything with it yet, so
here's where we get our error
addUser Not Yet implemented.
So notice we're following the
Node.js convention of the
first argument to the callback
being an error object and the
second argument being the actual
data we're returning.
So when you implement this,
you want actually callback
with an error here if some error
occurred and callback
with potentially some value
if you've succeeded
in adding the user.
So you're going to actually have
to look a little bit in
the sessions.js file that uses
the user data access object to
get a sense of how this is being
used and what kind of
callback is passed in.
So your job is to fill in this
code right here to add a user
when one tries to sign up.
All right.
So now let's look at
the next function.
All right.
So this is the validate login
function, and this one's a
little bit more complicated
but most of the work is
actually factored out in this
validateUserDoc function.
So we'll briefly go over that
and see which parts of that
you have to implement.
So validate login function takes
a username and password
and a callback, and the way the
callback works is it will
either return a user if we found
a user and our password
looks right or it will callback
with an error if
we've had a database error or
an invalid password or our
user doesn't exist.
So if we look down here, we
can see that we're not
actually getting any document
from MongoDB.
So this is what you need to do
to make this function work for
homework 2-3 is actually
get the user
document from MongoDB.
So this function's actually
complete and kind of
encapsulates all the work you
need to do after getting the
document, including checking
the error object.
So once you actually make the
call to MongoDB, you can just
use this function directly.
You can just pass the error
object and the user document
straight to this function
and it should hook up.
All right.
So that's the big crash course
on how our blog project works
and an introduction
to homework 2-3.
So just to recap, this is
our main, these are
our routes for express--
they contain some helpers that
describe the work we need to
do for each route and actually
register the routes--
and these three files
are our data
access objects to MongoDB.
So they have helper functions
for accessing or modifying the
various collections.
So for homework 2-3, you'll
be modifying the users.js
collection so that
login and sign up
actually works correctly.