Welcome to M101JS, MongoDB
for Node.js developers.
My name is Andrew Erlichson,
and I'll be teaching this
course along with Shaun Verch
and Richard Kreuter.
I'm going to be teaching the
more general MongoDB parts,
and Shaun is to be teaching the
Node.js parts, and Richard
mostly shows up in the second
week, where he goes through
all the ins and outs of
the MongoDB shell
and the query language.
I'm VP of education here at
10gen, Shaun is a software
engineer, and Richard Kreuter
is a consulting engineer.
So, let's go through the
logistics for the course.
All right, this is going to be
a seven week online course,
and it is made up of several
different parts.
One part is the video lectures,
much like you are
watching right now.
And then at the end of
many of the video
lecture, there are quizzes.
And these video lectures are
short segments, typically
three to five minutes long,
and the quizzes are little
learning checks at the very
end of each video lecture.
Not everyone has one,
but many do.
At the end of each week,
you're going to have a
homework assignment, and then at
the end, there is going to
be a final exam.
Now, the video lectures,
in terms of your
grade, they do not count.
So they count for 0%
of your grade.
You can watch them or not, but
we recommend it, because
that's really the meat
of the class.
The quizzes count for 0%.
They're meant as little learning
checks to make sure
that you understand it,
as I said earlier.
And the homeworks count for
50% of your grade, and the
final exam counts for
50% of your grade.
Now, we're going to drop
the lowest homework.
And by drop lowest homework,
we mean that at the end of
each week there's homework, and
then for the week where
you get the lowest overall score
in the homework, we'll
drop that week.
If you have a perfect
square, we'll drop
some arbitrary week.
At the very end of the course
there's a final exam, and then
overall, if you get 65% or
better, then you will get a
certificate of completion.
And the certificate of
completion will look a little
bit better than this,
obviously.
It's going to be delivered to
you in PDF form, typically
within a couple weeks of
finishing the class.
It will have your name and the
version of MongoDB that you
used with the course.
And it will be signed
by probably myself
and somebody else.
And so if you complete the
course with 65% or better,
you'll get a certificate
of completion
from us for the course.
So, all right, it is now time
for our first quiz.
What counts toward your final
grade in this class?
Quizzes, homeworks, final exam,
or class participation?
Check all that apply.