All right, so let's talk about
the system requirements for
this course.
So first there's the
operating system.
So we'll make sure everything in
the course works on Mac OSX
and Windows 7.
So you can also run it on Linux,
and everything should
work there as well.
And let us know, actually, if
you're running this on Linux
and run into issues, and we'll
help you get through them.
Now, as far as Node.js, you
should be fine just using the
latest version of Node.js, and
actually, if you look on their
page, you can see the
system requirements
for installing Node.js.
So let's take a quick
look at that.
So here we're on the Node.js
site, and what you can do is
you can click on Downloads.
And here we can actually
see all the
different options available.
So all of these should work.
Just find your system here and
download the right installer.