All right.
So this is going to be
a quick introduction
to the Mongo Shell.
This is actually a terminal
window open in Mac OS X. Just
a Shell prompt right here.
So if you have MongoDB installed
globally on your
system and you have a running
MongoDB instance, you should
just be able to type mongo,
and the Mongo Shell will
automatically connect to the
running MongoDB instance.
So now we can do things like
show dbs, and show the
databases on this instance.
So this just gives us a list of
the databases that we have
currently stored.
So you can do something
like use demo.
So note that our demo database
didn't actually appear in the
list above when we did show dbs,
and the reason for that
is our demo database doesn't
actually exist yet.
It'll actually be created
automatically when
we try to use it.
So, now we're in this demo
database, and we can do
something like db.things.find.
So what this actually does is
it says, all right, we're in
the demo db.
This is a special object in the
shell that we register,
and that's sort of the connector
through which we
interact with the database.
So when you do db.things.find,
what that's doing is it's
saying, using my current
database and the collection
things, we want to find all
the documents in that
collection.
So, notice we don't have
anything in that collection
right now, so we can insert
a very simple JSON object.
So what we can do is we can
do db.things.insert.
We can insert an object with a
key of a, a value of 1, and a
key of b, a value of 2, and
a key of c, value of 3.
All right, so now if we
go back up here, we do
db.things.find again, we can
see actually see that we
inserted the document.
So, notice that there's an extra
underscore ID field with
object ID, and this is a special
field automatically
generated by MongoDB, and used
internally by MongoDB, and
we'll talk about this
a little bit later.
So now let's try to insert
another JSON document.
So, let's do db.things.insert,
and let's try d of 4, e of 5,
and just insert to that.
So it looks like we have
a syntax error.
And if you look up here, you
can see that instead of a
colon to say, no, this is the
key for this value, we
actually have a comma here.
So, this is the token for going
to the next key in JSON
document, and we're using it
in the wrong place here.
So, let's redo that.
So, we were able to answer
that successfully.
Now if we do a db.things.find,
you see once again that we
have the underscore ID field,
and we have the
d of 4, e of 5.
So if we wanted to just find one
of these documents, we can
actually pass a JSON document
as a query specifier.
So instead of doing
db.things.find and finding
everything, we can do
db.things.find only documents
that have a field a and a value
of 1 for that field.
And we just find the
one document.
So, one more thing that I
haven't talked about as much
in this lecture is that we are
actually in a complete
JavaScript environment.
So, I've just done a few simple
commands, like an
insert and a find, but we can do
pretty much anything that's
supported by the v8
JavaScript engine.
So if we wanted to, we could
say, for var i equals 0, i
less than 10, i plus plus, and
we can actually say, for each
iteration of this loop,
db.things.insert.
the field x with the key of i.
So those will actually just go
through this loop, insert all
10 documents, then give a
[INAUDIBLE] the prompt.
So now we can do
db.things.find.
You notice we have 10 new
documents inserted, so that's
just one example of how you
could actually use the fact
that this is a complete
JavaScript environment with
the MongoDB operations.
All right, so here's
our next quiz.
Which of the following
expressions
are valid JSON documents?
So select all that apply.