All right, so let's talk about
how to install Node.js on Mac
OS X. So, the first thing we
want to do is we want to open
our browser, and enter
nodejs.org.
So this will bring us to the
node.js site, and at this
point, all we have to do is
click Install, and it will try
to download the installer
for Node.js.
Here we say keep, and after it's
done downloading, we can
open it, and it brings
us straight
into the Node.js installer.
So here we just click
Continue, Continue.
Agree with the license
agreement, and click Install.
So, this requires the
administrator password to
install software, so
let's do that.
Click Install.
And we see that node was
successfully installed.
So here we have the two
binaries for our node
installation, and we have
to make sure that
this is in our path.
So the way you can check that
and verify that Node.js is
actually installed is just go
to a terminal and type node.
So at this point, it'll bring
us into the Node.js
interactive prompt, and
we can just say
console.log Hello, World.
So that's how you install
Node.js on Mac OS X.