All right.
So, now we're going to talk
about building a Hello World
application using MongoDB and
the MongoDB Node.js driver.
What is the Node.js driver?
What does it mean to be
a driver for MongoDB?
This is a little bit of our
overall architecture.
We have our Mongod server
listening here for incoming
connections.
And it actually expects
BSON protocol.
So, this is a binary JSON.
And there's a specific protocol
for communicating
with the database.
And the idea behind a driver is,
the driver actually is a
library in a specific
language--
in this case, JavaScript--
that will actually handle this
protocol and handle this
communication, handle opening
sockets, handle, handle
detecting errors, handle
connecting to replica sets,
handle a lot of things behind
the scenes that you don't want
to have to deal with in
your application code.
So, the idea is that you'll
actually include the driver
for MongoDB, to Node.js driver,
and you'll use it in
your application just like you
would any other library.
And it'll actually deal
with communicating
to MongoDB for you.
In this lesson, we'll talk
about how to install the
Node.js driver and how to use
its API to actually connect to
MongoDB and to read
a document.
So, let's take a look.
Here we have our app.js file.
This is our example application
that we're going
to use to understand
the Node.js gesture
and how to use it.
But before we get started, let's
actually try to run it
to make sure our application
is complete.
All right.
So, when we try to run our
application, we notice a
problem here.
We see that we cannot
find module MongoDB.
The MongoDB driver for Node.js
is actually a module.
So, here we can see that we
can't find the module, which
means we don't have our
dependency installed.
We don't have the MongoDB
driver installed.
So, the way we do that is, we
use the package manager and
just install MongoDB.
All right, so, now we have our
MongoDB driver installed.
If we look in our directory,
we see app.js and we see a
node_modules file where the
MongoDB driver is installed as
a module locally.
Now if we do node app.js, run
our application, we can see we
called fineOne.
We got back this document with
the name of MongoDB and this
nice message here.
So, let's take a look
at this application.
Up here at the top,
we actually have
this require statement.
Notice we require MongoDB.
It's actually the same
name that we used
to install the module.
And from that module, we're
actually getting this
MongoClient object.
So, this object is actually our
interface into the MongoDB
driver library.
And through this MongoClient
object, that's how we'll
access the API methods to the
driver, which will then handle
whatever operation
we requested.
Now that we have this
MongoClient object, we can go
down here and see that the first
thing we have to do is
actually open the connection
to the server.
So, this line here doesn't
actually do anything.
It's just basically getting us
this object that we can use to
interact with the driver.
So, the real work actually
happens in this connect call.
So, right here we have
MongoClient.connect, and we
have this connection
string here.
This is actually a special
connection string that the
driver understands.
And it uses this to connect to
our running Mongod server.
So, here we have MongoDB colon
slash localhost 27017,
basically saying that we're
connecting to a Mongod running
on our local machine on the
default port, which is 27017.
So, if you run Mongod with no
arguments, this is the port
that the database will
be listening on.
And at the end of the connection
string, we have
this slash test, which is
basically saying, connect to
the test database within
this Mongod server.
The interesting thing here is
that we're not actually
checking the return value.
What we do instead is, we
pass in a callback here.
So, what's happening is that
we call MongoClient.connect
with this connection string
in this callback.
The driver will say, OK, I'm
going to connect to this
Mongod instance, and I'm
actually going to call this
call back when I'm
done connecting.
You notice this call back
actually has two arguments.
So, because we're not checking
the return value here, we need
a way for the driver to be able
to tell us what happened,
give us the results of this
connection attempt.
Here in the standard Node.js
style, the first argument here
is an error object.
This will basically be set if
any kind of error occurred.
So, we can actually check that,
which we do right here,
to see if we need to abort
what we're trying to do.
How do these two arguments
actually get populated?
What's really happening here
is that we're calling this
connect call, sending
in this URL.
The driver is connecting to the
database, and when it's
done connecting, it'll actually
call this callback
that we've passed in.
So, if there's an error, this
error object is populated and
we throw the error.
If the connection was
successful, the driver will
actually call this callback
that we passed in with the
connected database object.
This object is also part
of the driver.
You can think of it kind of as
a handle for our database
connection.
So, from now on in this function
in our call back, we
can use this database object
to perform operations using
this already connected client.
If we look down here, we can
see that we're taking our
connect database object, calling
db.collection coll to
tell the driver which
collection
we're interested in.
Then we're doing a findOne
against that collection with
no query selector, and we're
also giving that a call back.
So, again, this call back is
passed inside the driver and
it will get called when the
operation is complete.
And if there was some kind of
error, the driver will pass in
the error object with some
information about what happened.
And, if the query was performed
successfully, this
second argument, doc, will
be populated with the
result of our query.
So, in here, we can check the
error, we can print the
result, and then we just close
the database connection.
So, again, this is our
connected DB object.
We're still referencing the
one that we got in our
original connect call back,
and we can just close it.
Down here, we actually
say called findOne.
Notice that this will different
first because of our
asynchronous model of calling
this function and not waiting
for a return, but instead
passing a call back to say
call this call back
when you're done.
So, it'll actually execute this
line, then execute this
line, then this callback will
get called after the round
trip to the server.
All right.
So, this is a basic Hello World
application using the
MongoDB Node.js driver.
So, let's just run this
one more time.
Node app.js.
Now we know that what's actually
happening here is
that we're connecting
to the database.
And then, once we've connected,
we actually do a
find one and print out
that we called it.
And then when we get
the response,
we'll print the document.
So, that's the basic Hello World
application using the
MongoDB Node.js driver.