All right.
So now let's do a simple
Hello World
application using Express.
So, Express is a library for
Node.js, which handles a lot
of routing, and a lot of
the details of a web
application for us.
So to get started, let's
do what we did before.
Let's do mkdir hello_express.
Change into it.
And now that we're in here, we
can say, in any text editor
again, we just open app.js.
So the first thing we want
to do is we want to get a
reference to our module.
So let's just say our express
equals require express.
So this will give us a reference
to the module, and
now let's just create an
instance of our app.
All right, so now the first
thing we want to do is
register handler for route.
So now let's do app.get for
slash, and give it a call back
for when this route
is requested.
And give it the request,
and an object for
dealing with the response.
All right, so what is this
actually doing here?
The app.get method is a way to
tell Express how to handle a
get request to a
particular URL.
So in this example, we are
telling Express that all get
requests to the resource slash,
meaning the URL with
nothing after it, should be
handled by this function we're
passing in.
Notice that the callback
takes two arguments.
These are the request and
response objects, and our
paths do our call back by
Express, so we can use them in
our route handling code.
So in the body here, what we
want to do is actually handle
this request.
So, we know from the context
that the request has been made
to slash, and at this point we
don't really care about doing
something different, so let's
just, any time someone
requests this resource,
let's just do
result.send, Hello, World.
And then down here, let's do
app.listen on port 8080, then
log a nice message, saying that
our server was started.
So what we can do is
go node, app.js.
So now we have an
issue similar to
the one we had before.
We need the express module.
So what we do is we just type
npm install express.
All, right so our module's
installed.
Now if we do node, app.js,
we see Express server
started on port 8080.
Now if we go to our browser,
we can just go local host,
8080, and we get Hello, World.
So, one issue with this is that
now if we go to something
other than just slash, so we
go local host, 8080, not
found, we just get this
message, cannot
get slash not found.
And that's from Express,
basically saying there is no
route registered here.
So let's fix that.
Let's go back to our
application, and we'll
register a new route on star.
And basically, star
is wild card.
It means any route that was
not handled by a previous
handler falls down, and gets
handled by this one.
So now we basically have a
handler for any of our routes.
So, what we can do here is we
can just say do result.send,
page not found, and
give a 404.
So now if we run our application
again, we can go
back to the browser, try to
reload the page, and instead
of the cannot get, we get
a page not found.
So, that's the basics of setting
up a simple Hello,
World application on Express.