All right, so, we covered
writing a Hello World
application using express, and
we covered writing a Hello
World application using express
and swig, and we
covered writing a simple
Hello World
application using MongoDB.
So now let's combine
that all together.
As a starting point, we'll use
the app from our last lecture,
which includes express and swig,
and we'll just be adding
calls to MongoDB to
this application.
First thing we want
to do is add our
dependencies to MongoDB.
So, we'll get the MongoClient
first and say MongoClient
equals require MongoDB dot
MongoClient, and then we'll
say server equals require
MongoDB dor server.
You'll see why I do this
a little bit later.
But the server is also from
our MongoDB driver module.
So, now down here we'll actually
create our object
describing our MongoDB
connection.
So, we'll go var mongoclient
equals new MongoClient, new
server localhost 27017, and
let's tell it to use the
native BSON parser.
All right, so one thing to note
is that, after this line,
we actually have not
established a
connection to MongoDB.
So, this line is just setting up
our connection information.
This is creating an object that
describes how we want to
connect to MongoDB.
So, this call is synchronous.
This call immediately returns
at, we're not actually
registering a call back.
So, first thing we'll do we'll
just say var db equals
mongoclient.db, and let's
use the course database.
So, it's the same thing here.
We're actually doing
mongoclient.db, and it's just
giving us a reference to a
database, but it's not a
database that's connected yet.
There's actually no connection
to MongoDB at this point.
So, we're going to do something
that seems a little
bit strange, but hopefully later
it will make more sense.
So, we're actually going to use
db, even though it doesn't
look like it's connected
at this point, and go
db.collection hello mongo
express dot findOne function
error and then return
document.
And then in the body of
this call back, we'll
actually do this here.
We'll render our page, but
instead of passing in this
document, we'll actually pass
in the document that was
returned from MongoDB.
And note that this document
actually must have a name
field just like the literal
document we had before, so the
documents in hello mongo express
must have a name field
for it to show properly
in our swig template.
So, this may seem a
little strange.
It looks like we're using our
database reference before it's
actually connected, but now if
we go down here, you notice
that none of these functions can
actually get called until
we actually start listening.
So, what we do is, we actually
open our database
connection down here.
We actually say mongoclient.open
and pass in
the call back to call when
we have actually
connected to the database.
And inside the call back,
we'll start listening.
What this means is that we
actually start listening as
soon as the connection to
the database is open.
But, since we're not listening
before that point, these
actually don't get called until
we've actually opened
our connection.
Notice that each of these
callbacks also takes an error.
Right now I'm just
not handling it.
But in a real application, you'd
want to check the error
and stop at that point.
So, right here we could
actually say,
if error throw error.
This is very simple
error handling.
It just throws an exception
if we fail to connect the
database, rather than starting
to listen on our app server.
All right, so let's
try this out.
Let's try node app.js.
So now we see we have
our express server
listening on port 8080.
We can go back to our browser,
and we still have hello, Swig
sitting there.
But we go back, now let's
connect again
to local host 8080.
And we see hello, MongoDB.
So, I actually inserted
a document before
with the name MongoDB.
So, you can go back to our
shell and stop this.
We go mongo, and use course,
which is the database were
connecting to.
db.hello_mongo_express.find.
And we see that there's one
document with the name
MongoDB, and what happens is
that in our application, we
got the document from the
database, and we render it
using the same template we used
before, and what we're
seeing here, our browser is
hello.html, populated with the
contents of the document we
had stored in MongoDB.
So overall, the reason we see
MongoDB here is because our
templating engine is looking
for a name field in the
document we passed
in, and printing
whatever value it finds.
And the document we got from the
database and passed to our
template engine happened to
have a name field with a
string value of MongoDB.
So, that's why we see MongoDB
on the page here.
All right, so that's an example
of putting all of
these together with MongoDB
Express and Swig.
And those are actually all the
libraries that you need to
know about to understand how the
blog application for this
course actually works.
The blog application uses Swig
as a template engine, Express
is the router, and MongoDB is
the back end data store.