All right.
So we've talked a little bit
about building an application
on Node.js, and the different
libraries available.
Now let's talk a little bit
more about Express.
So, this section's optional, but
it's for anyone who wants
to get a little bit more details
of how to use Express,
but it's not required
for this course.
And you can actually
complete the course
without these two lectures.
So this is just for
any added benefit.
So, what we're going to cover
in this lecture are URL
parameters and GET variables.
So there are two ways that
Express could actually get
data from the client side
of an application.
So, this is our example
application that we'll be
using in this lesson, and we see
here that it's running on
local host 3,000, but it
does not have a route
registered for slash.
So let's actually navigate to
a specific resource, and see
what we get.
So I'm going to navigate
to slash name.
Here we get a message.
We say, hello, name, here
you're GET variables.
So, what's happening here is
that this part of the URL is
actually being read by our
application and printed back
to us right here.
So we see it's printing
out our GET variables.
We don't actually have any
GET variables, so let's
actually add some.
So let's add GET var
1 equals value.
So there we see we have our GET
variable, GET var 1 equals
value, after our URL.
And down here we see that
you get our value
printed back to us.
So, you could add another
GET variable.
And we see that get var
2 equals value 2.
You see that down here.
So, note that this is only
because we actually are
looking for GET var 1 and GET
var 2 in our application.
So if we try to enter another
GET variable, we see that it
has no effect, because our
application is only looking
for GET var 1 and GET var 2.
It's not actually looking
for not found.
All right, so this is what
we're trying to do.
Let's now take a look at the
example application code.
All right.
So this is our example.
We have up here our modules
that we're using.
So we're using Express, and
we're using consolidate just
to get our templating library,
and here we're registering our
templating library, registering
our router,
registering some error handling,
which I'll talk
about in a minute.
So let's take a look
at our route.
So if we go all the way down
to the bottom, you can see
we're registering just one
route, app.get, and our route
is slash colon name.
So, colon here actually has a
special meaning in a route
that you register
with Express.
What the colon is saying is take
this part of the URL and
store it in a variable
called name.
So, any variable captured this
way is actually put in the
request inside the
params object.
So if you want to access name,
you say request.params to get
the params object, which has
all the parameters that you
captured in the URL, and dot
name to get the name.
You could actually capture
multiple parameters in here,
so we could have colon name
slash colon something else,
slash colon something else.
They would all be put
in request.params.
So, now what about
GET variables?
So if we look at the next two
lines, this actually shows how
to extract get variables
in Express.
So the GET variables are
actually put in request.query.
So here we're saying we'll
accept two GET variables,
getvar1 and getvar2,
and just put them
in these local variables.
Finally, down here we render
the result using a template
that I'll show you in a moment,
that has name, getvar1
and getvar2.
So let's take a quick look
at the template.
All right, so this
is our template.
Here we just say hello, name,
and if you remember, that was
our parameter in the URL.
And we just say, here are
your GET variables.
And print out all the
GET variables.
So let's go back
to our example.
So, one thing I want to mention
here is that we can
still actually specify other
GET variables, and they'll
still be put in req.query, but
the only ones we're actually
looking at are getvar1
and getvar2, which
may actually be undefined.
So, one thing you could do in
this case, if this is what you
were looking for, is just check
if it's undefined, set
it to some default value.
You could also iterate the
req.query object to see all
the GET variables that the user
said, and put them out
for debugging purposes.
But that's the basic idea
behind GET variables.
All right, so let's run this
and see how it looks.
So, we have our Express server
listening on port 3,000.
So let's go open that
in the browser.
So we go to local is 3,000, and
we see cannot GET slash.
So the reason for that is we
actually specified colon name
after the slash.
So, we want to capture the
result after the slash, and
name, which means we actually
have to specify
some kind of path.
So if we go back up here and
do slash Shaun, say hello,
Shaun, here are your
GET variables.
So notice we didn't actually
check if our get variables
were undefined, and
we just sort of
put them in our template.
So in this case, since they're
undefined, we just see two
empty bullets.
So we can go up here and
add our GET variables.
So it was getvar1, and now we
see we have variable 1 set in
our template, and we
could do the same
thing, and say getvar2.
All right, so that's how to
get GET variables and URL
parameters using Express.
So, here's the URL parameter.
Here are the two GET variables.