All right, now let's talk about
handling post requests
in Express.
So, what we have here is we have
an example application
with a simple form that allows
a user to pick their favorite
fruit, and then submit the form,
which will generate a
post request to our
Express app.
So if we click here and submit
it, this will generate a post
request to slash favorite
fruit, and the express
application will reply with your
favorite fruit is apple.
So this is the example we'll be
discussing, and we'll see
the code behind this.
So let's take a look at
our example code.
All right, so this is our
example of using post
variables with Express, and up
here we have our modules.
We're using the same
templating engine.
We have this extra line here,
which I'll talk about in a
bit, and we have our error
handler, which I'll actually
talk about in this section.
So, let's take a look
at our routes.
All right, so we actually
have two routes here.
One is a get, and
one is a post.
So, basically when we get slash,
we render our fruit
picker template, which I'll
show you in a bit.
But basically, this
is just a form.
It allows users to select what
their favorite food is among
the choices given here.
So, here we have fruits, which
is an array, apple, orange,
banana, peach.
This is going to be posted
in the fruit picker form.
So, when the user submits the
form, it'll submit a post
request to slash
favorite fruit.
So, this is actually where we
handle the form submission.
So, the way we handle post
requests is by accessing the
variables in request.body.
So here we say, favorite equals
request.body.fruit.
But there's something you
actually have to pay
attention to here.
So, we're looking this
request.body object, but it's
only populated if we register
the body parser middleware.
So if we go up here near the
top, you notice that I have
this extra line, app.use
express.bodyParser.
So what this is doing
is it's registering
middleware with Express.
So, what does that mean?
So when you register a
middleware function, you're
basically telling Express
I want to do this extra
processing.
And since we have this extra
processing before app.router,
the processing in
express.bodyParser will happen
before we hit any
of our routes.
So, app.router is sort of a way
to specify when you want
your routes to be called.
So, Express actually has
different middleware for
different purposes.
But in this case,
express.bodyParser, for our
purposes, will parse the body
of the request and populate
request.body, so we can access
it in our route below.
All right, so this is kind of a
small diversion, but I just
wanted to show you this
for reference.
If you want to see the different
kinds of middleware
available for Express, you can
actually go to expressjs.com,
which is the home page, look at
the API reference, and go
down to middleware, and
you can see all
the middleware available.
So right here we have
bodyParser, which
we were just using.
And body parsing middleware
actually wraps a few other
functions, but for our purposes,
we just care about
the fact that it's parsing
our post variables.
All right, so that's where you
can go for reference, if
you're ever wondering what
middleware to use.
All right, so we've registered
our bodyParser middleware,
which means that down here,
we can just use
request.body.fruit.
However, if the user didn't
pick one and submitted the
form anyway, fruit will
be undefined.
So we actually have to check
for that, and we'll talk a
little bit about this special
error handling later.
If the user did pick a fruit,
we say response.send, your
favorite fruit is, and then
whatever the favorite fruit is
that they picked.
All right, so before we run it,
let's just take a quick
look at our templates.
So, here we have fruit
picker.html, basically just a
form, and it's iterating over
fruits, saying for fruit and
fruits, create a new input
field for each fruit
that we passed in.
So, this is just our template
using our fruits array.
All right, so we've
run our app.
We have our server listening
on port 3,000, so let's go
open that in a browser.
All right, so here we have
our fruit picker form.
What is your favorite fruit?
And let's just pick
the first one.
Submit, and it says, your
favorite fruit is apple.
So, let's go back to
our application.
So I want to talk a little
bit about this
error handler function.
So in Express, you can
register functions
specifically to deal
with errors.
The way you do that is you
actually specify a function
with four arguments.
First the error object, then the
request object, then the
response object, then this next
call back, which we'll
talk about below.
All right, s if we go back to
our route, we can see that we
have a request object, the
response object, and
this next call back.
So this third argument, next, is
actually a function passed
in by Express, along with the
request and response objects.
And one of the things we can do
with it is we can actually
use it to handle errors.
So here we say, if type of
favorite equals undefined, we
say next error, please
choose a fruit.
So, by passing an error object
to next, we're telling Express
that we've had some
kind of error.
And what Express does at
that point is it tries
to handle the error.
And the way it does it is by
looking for any error handling
middleware that we may have
registered earlier.
So if we go back up here a
little bit, we can see this is
our error handling middleware,
and when you call next with an
error object, Express will say,
OK, we've had an error,
let's find any error handling
middleware that's been
registered, and call it.
So what this will do is it will
log our error message.
It'll log the stack trace
for our error.
It'll return a server error
status, and it'll render the
error template to the user.
So, let's try that out.
So we have our server listening
on port 3,000 again.
Let's go back to our
picker page.
Now what happens if
we submit without
picking any of our fruit?
All right, so here we actually
have an error logged from the
server, because we called next
with our error object, and
express new to call our error
handling middleware.
So if we go back here, we'll
actually see this huge stack
trace, because in our error
handling middleware, we
actually printed out a stack
trace, in addition to
rendering the error page.
All right, so that was a quick
introduction to using post
variables in Express, using
some basic middleware, and
registering middleware
to handle any
errors that you have.