So, we have three homework
assignments for week one.
The first one is just to run
the Mongo Restore command.
This is just to get some data
into MongoDB, so that we can
actually play around
with it and do some
interesting things with it.
So this is just basic, getting
started, run the
Mongo Restore command.
We have a dump provided that we
generated using Mongo Dump
earlier, and that's provided
as part of the course file.
So let's get started and talk
about homework 1-1-.
So, first thing you'll want to
do is go on the course website
and download the files
for the homework.
This will be in a zip file, so
I'll just show you how to
extract those on a Mac, and
these command should be the
same on Linux.
So, just say tar xvzf,
hm1-1.tar.
So now we extracted homework
1-1, and here we just have a
single directory dump.
So at this stage, you want to
make sure that you actually
have MongoDB running
on your system.
So if you've actually installed
MongoDB and have the
permissions set up correctly,
you should be able to just
type mongod dash dash dbpath
slash data slash db.
And now we have our
server running.
It's waiting for connections
on the default
port on local host.
So, once we've made sure that
mongod is actually running and
waiting for connections, we
can type mongo restore.
dump.
So what Mongo Restore does is
it descends into the dump
directory, looking for files
to import, connects to
MongoDB, and imports
these files.
So, notice that our directory
had a single database, n101,
with three different
collections.
Homework 1-1, homework 1-2,
and homework 1-3.
So, that's how you run Mongo
Restore, and your assignment
for homework 1-1 is to actually
use the Mongo shell,
and figure out what's in the
homework 1-1 collection.