All right.
So, this is the homework
1-1 answer video.
So, your assignment for this
homework was to, using the
Mongo shell go into the m101
database and figure out what's
in the homework 1_1
collection.
So, the first thing
you need to do is
start the Mongo shell.
And we actually don't need to
give it any arguments at this
point, because we've started the
server on the default port
on local host, which is the
default that the Mongo shell
tries to connect to.
So, we run the shell and we can
see MongoDB shell version
2.4.3 connecting to test.
So, we're now connected to the
test database, and we really
want to be connected to
the m101 database.
So, the first thing we do is,
we type use m101, and we see
switch to db m101.
And the next thing we can
do is type show tables.
So, now we see all the
collections in this database.
Homework 1_1, homework 1_2,
homework 1_3, and
system.indexes.
So, the assignment for this part
was to see what's in the
homework 1_1 collection.
So, we can do that by doing a
find against this collection.
Here we have db.hw1_1.find,
and this will do a query
against our collection.
And if we run that, we can see
that we get one document back.
It had an ID, and it has an
answer field which says, hello
from MongoDB.
So, that's the answer
to homework 1-1/