All right.
So if you remember, homework
1-3 was to run our
application, which is
Hello World using
Node.js Express and Swig.
So if we look in our folder, we
see we have app.js, we have
package.json, and
we have views.
So we have package.json here
because our file has multiple
dependencies, and this just
describes the dependencies of
our project.
So we can actually just type
npm install, and it will
actually read the package.json
file and install the
dependencies.
So now we can just
run node app.js.
We can see express server
started on port 8080.
So if we go to a browser and try
to connect to local post
8080, we see Hello, Agent 007.
So this is the answer
for homework 1-3.