If you want to learn more about
GridFS a good place to
start is api.mongodb.org.
If you go there and you click
on the Java driver and you
click on the most recent driver
right there, you can
see that the specification
for GridFS, the
API, is right there.
And you can see the three
different classes that I used
to work with GridFS, right,
which is this GridFS object
right here, this GridFS db
file which is used for
retrieving objects, and this
GridFS input file which is
used for writing GridFS files
into the database and taking
an output stream from a disk.
And then I didn't actually use
this GridFS file, which is
abstract class or the CLI.
You can go through these
and you can see a
lot of the same methods.
So this is a good place to look
if you're looking for
more information.