So now let's talk about
homework number
two for week three.
So for this homework we'll be
revisiting the blog project
and actually add the ability
to make new posts.
So you actually should have
already added the ability to
Login and Logout and to make
a new user, but if not--
if you had some issues with
that, we're actually going to
give you a new stencil that has
those sections included so
you can go check your work on
the parts that you filled in
last week and the parts that
you already filled in.
So for this homework we're
actually going to be adding
the ability to make new posts.
So right now we're logged in as
the user test, so let's go
up here and click on New Post.
All right, so far so good.
We're on the new post page.
Let's make a title of new post
and entry of entry and let's
just go down here and let's
submit this form.
All right, so here we get an
error insertEntry NYI, so that
gives us a hint as to what
we're actually missing.
So it's actually the
post request.
When we try to make a new post
we need this insert entry
function to actually
insert the post
entry into our database.
So let's take a look at
the code for that.
So down here we have this stack
trace because we're
missing the insertEntry function
so let's stop this.
So the way you can find out what
you need to implement for
this project is you can just run
this command and you get
back posts.js line 32,
homework 3.2 TODO.
So let's open posts.js.
So we look at this file and we
can see this is the posts data
access object and one of the
things we do here is we say
var posts equals
db.collection.posts.
So you can actually use this to
perform operations against
the post collection so you don't
actually have to use
this db object directly.
So if we go down here--
the getPosts function-- we can
see an example of using it.
We're using posts.find.sort and
giving it some arguments.
And this is just an example of
using this posts object.
It's equivalent to doing
db.collection posts.find.
Just wanted to show
how you use that.
All right, so let's take a
look at what we have to
implement for homework 3.2.
So if we look up here
we can see we have
this insertEntry function.
So a lot of this is
done for you.
We're making this post, we have
the permalink, and we've
built this entire post object--
this is complete.
Now all you have to do is figure
out how to insert it
into the posts collection.
So down here we see our call
back with the error message
that we saw when we tried to
open this page and tried to do
this operation when we were in
the browser and the stack
trace we saw in the shell.
So just to take a look at
surrounding code, this is the
insertEntry function and
basically takes title, body,
tags, author, callback.
And actually all the code to
build this post and actually
create this post object
is all done for you.
All the processing, all the
sanitizing input is done for
you, so all you really need to
do is figure out how to insert
this post into the
posts collection.
So this will actually give us
support for creating a new
post and this is your assignment
for homework 3.2.