So the goal of this homework
is to allow us
to comment on posts.
So we already have these
posts, and we
want to add a comment.
So let's try to do that.
So here on the second post--
it says "Next post"--
we have our name, we have our
email, and let's add a comment
of "foo."
We try to submit this, we get
an error, addComment not yet
implemented.
So the assignment for homework
3.3 is to allow users to
comment on blog posts.
So if we go back to where we run
our app, we see the stack
trace from our error handler.
So similar to the way you found
homework 3.2, you could
do a similar search for
homework 3.3 to do.
We see it's in the same file.
It's also in posts.js.
So that's actually the place
that has the code for handling
comments in a post.
All right.
So this is the function
you need to fill out
for homework 3.3.
So this is the addComment
function.
Here we get a permalink, name,
email, body, and a callback.
So this code here makes our
comment, fills in the email of
the comment, and your job is to
actually implement adding
the callback to a post.
Now, if you remember from the
schema of the blog, the
comments are actually in an
array inside of a post.
So you're going to actually have
to figure out how to add
a comment to a single post.
And the permalink is actually
what describes which post
you're trying to add
this comment to.
So that's the assignment
for homework 3.3.